<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Second collection of the newest and most ingenious poems, satyrs, songs, &amp;c. against popery and tyranny relating to the times : most of which never before printed.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 142KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 15 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A58964</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13242319</idno>
  <idno type="VID">98643</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240898273</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing S2266</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R7993</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">13242319</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A58964)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 98643)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 438:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A Second collection of the newest and most ingenious poems, satyrs, songs, &amp;c. against popery and tyranny relating to the times : most of which never before printed.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 5-31 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1689.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">English wit and humor.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-12 </date>
            <label>Alexis (Ali) Jakobson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-12 </date>
            <label>Alexis (Ali) Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:98643:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:98643:1"/>
            <p>A SECOND COLLECTION OF The Newest and Most Ingenious <hi>Poems, Satyrs, Songs,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>AGAINST Popery and Tyranny, Relating to the TIMES.</p>
            <p>Most of which never before Printed.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed in the Year MDCLXXXIX.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="table_of_contents">
            <pb facs="tcp:98643:2"/>
            <head>The CONTENTS.</head>
            <list>
               <item>THE Dream of the Cabal, a Prophetick Satyr; writ <hi>1672.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>The History of <hi>Insipids,</hi> A Lampoon.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Stafford</hi>'s Ghost.</item>
               <item>On the D—ss of <hi>P—th</hi>'s Picture.</item>
               <item>A New Song of the Times, <hi>1683.</hi> Or the Whiggish-Plot.</item>
               <item>A Dialogue between Father <hi>Petres</hi> and the <hi>Devil.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>To the Bra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>n-Head.</item>
               <item>The Answer.</item>
               <item>An Epitaph on <hi>Al. Sydney.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>A Stanza put on <hi>Westminster-hall</hi> Gate.</item>
               <item>On Easter-day <hi>87.</hi> this was found fixed on the King's Chapel Door.</item>
               <item>To the Prince of <hi>Orange,</hi> A Pacquet of Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, with the Pacquet-Boat return'd.</item>
               <item>The Story of the Pet▪ and the Kettle: as it was told by Collonel <hi>T—s,</hi> the Night be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore he Kist the <hi>K—s</hi> hand.</item>
               <item>On <hi>Rome</hi>'s Pardons, by the E. of <hi>R.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>A New Song, to the Tune of <hi>Lilli-burlero.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Popery Pickled: Or, the Jesuit Shooes made of <hi>Running Leather.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>The Second Part of <hi>Lilli-burlero bullen a-la.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Monmouth's</hi> Remembrance.</item>
               <item>A New Song of the <hi>French</hi> Kng's fear of an <hi>Orange.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>A Letter to the Lord Chancellor, exposing to him the Sentiments of the People, with some pertinent Advice in the conclusion.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Dangerfield's</hi> Ghost to <hi>Jeffreys.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>A Congratulatory Poem to his Royal Highness the Prince of <hi>Orange.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>A Congratulatory Poem to his Royal Highness the Prince of <hi>Orange,</hi> or his Welcom to the City of <hi>London.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>To make a Catholick Pudding.</item>
               <item>Ʋpon the execrable Murther of the Right Honourable <hi>Arthur</hi> Earl of <hi>Essex.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>A true Account of a late Conference between the wonderful speaking Head, and Father <hi>Pulton.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>An <hi>Irish</hi> Prophesie.</item>
               <item>The Deponents.</item>
               <item>Father <hi>Petres</hi>'s Policy discovered, a Song to the Tune of <hi>Lulla by Babee.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>A New Song to the Tune of <hi>Hey brave Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pery.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Sir <hi>Tho. J—s</hi> Speech to his Wife and Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren.</item>
               <item>On the <hi>P.</hi> of <hi>O.</hi> going to <hi>England</hi> with an Army to restore the Government.</item>
            </list>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:98643:2"/>
            <head>THE Dream of the Cabal, A Prophetick Satyr, <hi>Anno</hi> 1672.</head>
            <l>AS t'other Night in Bed I thinking lay,</l>
            <l>How I my Rent shou'd to my Landlord pay,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ince Corn, nor Wool, nor Beast would Money make;</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>umbling perplext, these Thoughts kept me awake.</l>
            <l>What will become of this mad World, quoth I?</l>
            <l>What's its Disease, what is its Remedy?</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>here will it issue, whereto do's it tend?</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ome ease to Misery 'tis to know its end.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ill Servants Dreaming, as they us'd to do,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>or'd me a sleep, I fell a Dreaming too.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>e thought there met the Grand Cabal of Seven,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Odd numbers some men say do best please Heaven)</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>hen sat they were, and Doors were all fast shut,</l>
            <l>secret was behind the Hangings put:</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>oth hear and see I could; but he that there</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ad placed me, bad me have as great a care</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>f stirring, as my life: and ere that out</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>om thence I came, resolv'd shou'd be my Doubt.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>hat would become of this Mad World, unless</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>resent Designs were cross'd with ill success?</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>n awful Silence there was held some space,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ill trembling, thus began one call'd his Grace.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>reat Sir, your Government for first twelve years</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>as spoil'd the Monarchy, and made our Fears</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> potent on us, that we must change quite</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>h' old Foundations, and make new, wrong or right.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>or too great mixture of Democracy</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ithin this Government allay'd must be;</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>nd no allay like nulling Parliaments</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>'th' Peoples Pride and Arrogance, the events</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>actious and Saucy, disputing Royal Pleasure,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ho your Commands by their own Humours measure.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>or King in Barnacles (and to th' Rack-Staves ty'd)</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ou must remain, if these you will abide.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>o spake the Long-blue Ribbon, then a Second,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>hough not so tall, yet quite as Wise is reckon'd,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>id thus begin, Great Sir, you are now on</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> tender Point much to be thought upon,</l>
            <l>And thought on only; for by Ancient Law,</l>
            <l>'Twas Death to mention what my Lord foresaw,</l>
            <l>His trembling shew'd it, wherefore I'm so bold</l>
            <l>To advise it's standing, lest it shou'd be told</l>
            <l>We did attempt to change it, for so much</l>
            <l>Our Ancestors secur'd it, that to touch,</l>
            <l>Like Sacred Mount, 'tis Death; and such a Trick,</l>
            <l>I no ways like my Tongue should break my Neck.</l>
            <l>Thus said, he sat. Then Lord of Northern Tone,</l>
            <l>In Gall and Guile a second unto none,</l>
            <l>Inraged rose, and Chol'rick, thus began,</l>
            <l>Dread Majesty, Male beam of Fame, a Son</l>
            <l>Of th' hundred and tenth Monarch of the Nore;</l>
            <l>De'l split the Weam of th' Lowne that spoke afore,</l>
            <l>Shame faw the Cragg of that ill manner'd Lord,</l>
            <l>That nent his King durst speak so faw a word;</l>
            <l>And aw my Saul, right weell the first man meant,</l>
            <l>De'l hoop his Luggs, that loves a Parliament.</l>
            <l>Twa Houses aw my Saul are too too mickle,</l>
            <l>They'll gar the Leard shall ne'er have more a prickle;</l>
            <l>No Money get to gee the bonny Lass,</l>
            <l>But full as good be Born without a—</l>
            <l>Ten thousand Plagues light on his Cragg (that gang)</l>
            <l>To make you be but third part of a King.</l>
            <l>De'l take my Saul, I'll ne'er the matter mince.</l>
            <l>I'd rather Subject be than sike a Prince,</l>
            <l>To Hang, and Burn, and Slay, and Draw, and Kill,</l>
            <l>And measure aw things by my awn gude will,</l>
            <l>Is Gay Dominion; a Cheekmate I hate,</l>
            <l>Of Men, or Laws, it looks so like a State.</l>
            <l>This eager well meant Zeal some Laughter stirr'd;</l>
            <l>Till Nose half plush, half Flesh, the Inkhorn Lord</l>
            <l>Crav'd Audience thus, Grave Majesty Divine,</l>
            <l>(Pardon that <hi>Cambridge</hi> Title, I make mine)</l>
            <l>We now are ent'red on the great'st Debate</l>
            <l>That can concern your Throne, and Royal State.</l>
            <l>His Grace hath so spoke all, that we who next</l>
            <l>Speak after, can but comment on his Text:</l>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:98643:3"/>
            <l>Only 'tis wonder at this sacred Board,</l>
            <l>Shou'd sit 'mongst us a <hi>Magna Charta</hi> Lord,</l>
            <l>A Peer of old Rebellious Barons breed,</l>
            <l>Worst, and great'st Enemies to Royal Seed.</l>
            <l>But to proceed; well was it urg'd by's Grace,</l>
            <l>Such Liberty was given for twelve years space</l>
            <l>That are by past, there's now necessity</l>
            <l>Of new Foundations, if safe you'll be.</l>
            <l>What Travel, Charge and Art, before was set</l>
            <l>This Parliament, we had; you can't forget;</l>
            <l>Now force, cajole, and court, and bribe for fear</l>
            <l>They wrong should run, e'er since they have been here.</l>
            <l>What diligence, what study, day and night,</l>
            <l>Was on us, and what care to keep them right?</l>
            <l>Wherefore (if good) you can't make Parliament,</l>
            <l>On whom such Costs, such Art, and Pains w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>re spent,</l>
            <l>And Moneys, all we had for them to do;</l>
            <l>Since we miss that, 'tis best dismiss them too.</l>
            <l>'Tis true this House the best is you can call,</l>
            <l>But in my judgment, best, is none at all:</l>
            <l>Well mov'd, the whole Cabal cry'd, Parliaments</l>
            <l>Are cloggs to Princes, and their brave intents.</l>
            <l>One did object, 'twas against Majesty</l>
            <l>To obey the Peoples pleasure. Another he</l>
            <l>Their inconvenience argues, and that neither</l>
            <l>Close their Designs were, nor yet speedy either.</l>
            <l>Whilst thus confused Chatter'd the Cabal,</l>
            <l>And many mov'd, none heard, but speak did all;</l>
            <l>A little bobtail'd Lord, Urchin of State,</l>
            <l>A <hi>Praise-God-b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>e-bone,</hi> Peer whom all men hate,</l>
            <l>Amphibious Animal, half Fool, half Knave;</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>egg'd silence, and this purblin'd Counsel gave:</l>
            <l>Blest and best Monarch, that e'er Sceptre bore,</l>
            <l>Renow'd for Vertue, but for Honour more;</l>
            <l>That Lord spake last, has well and wisely shown,</l>
            <l>That Parliaments, nor new, nor old, nor none</l>
            <l>Can well be trusted longer; for the State</l>
            <l>And Glory of the Crown, hate all Cheekmate.</l>
            <l>That Monarchy may from its Childhood grow</l>
            <l>To man's Estate; <hi>France</hi> has taught us how</l>
            <l>Monarchy's Divine; Divinity it shows,</l>
            <l>That he goes backward that not forward goes.</l>
            <l>Therefore go on, let other Kingdoms see</l>
            <l>Your Will's your Law, that's absolute Monarchy;</l>
            <l>A mixt hodg-podge will now no longer do,</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Caesar</hi> or nothing, You are brought unto:</l>
            <l>Strike then, Great Sir, 'fore these Debates take wind,</l>
            <l>Remember that Occasion's bald behind.</l>
            <l>Our Game is sure in this, if wisely Play'd,</l>
            <l>And sacred Votes to th'Vulgar not betray'd;</l>
            <l>But if the Rumor shou'd once get on wing.</l>
            <l>That we consult to make you abs'olute King.</l>
            <l>The <hi>Plebeians</hi> head, the Gentry, forsooth,</l>
            <l>They strait would short and have an aking Tooth;</l>
            <l>Lest they, I say, should your great Secrets scent,</l>
            <l>And you oppose in nulling Parliament.</l>
            <l>I think it safer, and a greater skill</l>
            <l>To obviate, than to or'e come an ill:</l>
            <l>For those that head the Herd are full as rude,</l>
            <l>When the humour takes, as th'following Multitude;</l>
            <l>Therefore be quick in your Resolves, and when</l>
            <l>Resolv'd you have, Execute quicker then.</l>
            <l>Remember your great Father lost the Game</l>
            <l>By slow Proceedings, may'nt you do the same?</l>
            <l>An unexpected, unregarded blow</l>
            <l>Wounds more than ten made by an open Poe.</l>
            <l>Delayes do Dangers breed, the Sword is yours</l>
            <l>By Law declar'd, what need of other Powers?</l>
            <l>We may unpolitick be judg'd, or worse,</l>
            <l>If we can't make the Sword command the Purse;</l>
            <l>No Art, or Courtship can the Rule so shape</l>
            <l>Without a Force, it must be done by Rape:</l>
            <l>And when 'tis done, to say you cannot help,</l>
            <l>Will satisfie enough the gentle Whelp.</l>
            <l>Phanaticks they'll to Providence impute</l>
            <l>Their Thraldom, and immediately grow mute;</l>
            <l>For they, poor pious Fools, think the Decree</l>
            <l>Of Heaven falls on them, though from Hell it be;</l>
            <l>And when their Reason is abas'd to it.</l>
            <l>They forthwith think't Religion to submit,</l>
            <l>And vainly glorying in a Passive shame,</l>
            <l>They'll put off man to wear the Christian name:</l>
            <l>Wherefore to lull'em, do their Hopes fulfill</l>
            <l>With Liberty, they're halter'd at your will;</l>
            <l>Give them but Conventicle-Room, and they</l>
            <l>Will let you steal the Englishman away,</l>
            <l>And heedless be, till you your Nets have spread,</l>
            <l>And pull'd down Conventicles on their head.</l>
            <l>Militia therefore and Parliaments cashier,</l>
            <l>A formidable standing Army rear,</l>
            <l>They'll mount you up, and up you soon will be,</l>
            <l>They'll fear who ne'er did love your Monarchy:</l>
            <l>And if they fear, no matter for their hate;</l>
            <l>To rule by Law becomes a sneaking State.</l>
            <l>Lay by all Fear, care not what People say,</l>
            <l>Regard to them will your Designs betray:</l>
            <l>When Bite they can't, what hurt can Barking do?</l>
            <l>And, Sir, in time we'll spoil their Barking too.</l>
            <l>Make Coffee-Clubs, talk of more humble things</l>
            <l>Than State Affairs, and Interest of Kings.</l>
            <l>Thus spake the Rigling Peer, when one more Grave,</l>
            <l>That had much less of Fool, but more of Knave,</l>
            <l>Began: Great Sir, it gives no small content,</l>
            <l>To hear such Zeal (for you) 'gainst Parliament;</l>
            <l>Wherefore, though I an Enemy no less</l>
            <l>To Parliaments than you your selves profess;</l>
            <l>Yet I must also enter my protest</l>
            <l>'Gainst these rude rumbling Counsels indigest.</l>
            <l>And, Great Sir, tell you, 'tis an harder thing</l>
            <l>Than they suggest, to make you abs'lute King;</l>
            <l>Old Buildings to pull down, believe it true,</l>
            <l>More danger in it hath, than building New.</l>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:98643:3"/>
            <l>And what shall prop your Superstructure till</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>nother you have built that suits your Will?</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>n Army shall, say they (content) but stay,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>rom whence shall this new Army have its pay?</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>or easie gentle Government a while</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ust first appear this Kingdom to beguile,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>he Peoples minds, and mak<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> them cry up you,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>or rasing Old, and making better New.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>or Taxes with new Government, all will blame,</l>
            <l>And put the Kingdom soon into a flame:</l>
            <l>For Tyranny has no such lovely look</l>
            <l>To catch men with, unless you hide the Hook;</l>
            <l>And no Bait hides it more than present Ease;</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ase but their Taxes, then do what you please.</l>
            <l>Wherefore, all wild debates laid by, from whence</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>hall Money rise to bear this vast expence?</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>or our first thoughts thus well resolved, we</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>n other things much sooner shall agree;</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>oin then with Mother Church, whose bosom stands</l>
            <l>Ope to receive us, stretching forth her Hands;</l>
            <l>Close but this Breach, and she will let you see</l>
            <l>Her Purse as open as her Arms, shall be.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>or sacred Sir by guess, I do not speak)</l>
            <l>Of poor she'll make you rich, and strong of weak.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>t home, abroad, no Money, no, nor Men,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>he'll let you lack, turn but to her again.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>he <hi>Scot</hi> could here no longer hold, but cry'd,</l>
            <l>De'l take the Pape, and all that's on his side;</l>
            <l>The Whore of <hi>Rome,</hi> that mickle man of Sin,</l>
            <l>Plague take the Mother, Bearns, and aw the Kin.</l>
            <l>What! racks my Saul! must we the Holy Rood</l>
            <l>Place in God's Kirk again? troth 'tis not gude,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> defy the Loon, the De'l and aw his works,</l>
            <l>The Pape shall lig no mare in God's gude Kirk.</l>
            <l>The <hi>Scot</hi> with Laughter check'd, they all agreed,</l>
            <l>The Lord spake last shou'd in his Speech proceed,</l>
            <l>Which thus he did; Great Sir, You know 'tis Season</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>alts all the motions that we make with reason;</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>nd now a season is afforded us,</l>
            <l>The best e'er came, and most propitious.</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>esides the Summ the Cath'licks will advance,</l>
            <l>You know the Offers we are made from <hi>France;</hi>
            </l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>nd to have Money and no Parliament,</l>
            <l>Must fully answer your design'd intent.</l>
            <l>And thus without tumultuous noise, or huff</l>
            <l>Of Parliaments, you may have Money enough;</l>
            <l>Which, if neglected now, there's none knows when</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ike Opportunities may be had again,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>or all to extirpate, now combined be,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>oth Civil and Religious Liberty.</l>
            <l>Thus Money you'll have to exalt the Crown,</l>
            <l>Without stooping Majesty to Country Clown.</l>
            <l>The triple League, I know, will be objected,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>s if that ought by us to be respected;</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ut who to Hereticks, or Rebell pay'th</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>he Truth ingag'd to by solemn Faith,</l>
            <l>Debaucheth Vertue, by those very things,</l>
            <l>The Church profaneth and debaseth Kings,</l>
            <l>As you your self have admirably shown,</l>
            <l>By burning Solemn Cov'nant, though your own;</l>
            <l>Faith, Justice, Truth, Plebeian Virtues be,</l>
            <l>Look well in them, but not in Majesty.</l>
            <l>For publick Faith is but a publick Thief,</l>
            <l>The greatest Cheat in Nature's vain Belief.</l>
            <l>The Second Lord, though check'd, yet did not fear,</l>
            <l>Impatient grew and could no longer bear,</l>
            <l>But rose in heat, and that a little rude</l>
            <l>The Lord's voice interrupts, and for Audience su'd:</l>
            <l>Great Majesty, Authentick Authors say,</l>
            <l>When hand was lifted up, <hi>Craesus</hi> to slay,</l>
            <l>The Father's danger on th' Dumb Son did make</l>
            <l>Such deep impressions that he forthwith spake.</l>
            <l>Pardon, Great Sir, if I, in imitation,</l>
            <l>Seeing the Danger to your Land and Nation,</l>
            <l>Do my resolv'd on silence also break,</l>
            <l>Although I see the matter, I shall speak,</l>
            <l>Under such disadvantages will fall,</l>
            <l>That it, as well as I, exploded shall;</l>
            <l>But vainly do they boast they Royal are,</l>
            <l>That can't for Princes good reflections bear;</l>
            <l>Nor will I call Compurgators to prove,</l>
            <l>What honour to the Crown I've born, with Love,</l>
            <l>My Acts have spoken, and sufficient are,</l>
            <l>Above what ere Detractors did, or dare.</l>
            <l>Wherefore, Great Sir, 'tis Ignorance, or hate</l>
            <l>Dictates these Counsels, you to precipitate.</l>
            <l>Foy say't again I will, not eat my word,</l>
            <l>No Councils Power, no, nor yet the Sword</l>
            <l>Can Old Foundations alter, or make New:</l>
            <l>Let Time interpret, who hath spoken true.</l>
            <l>Those Country Gentry, with their Beef and Bacon,</l>
            <l>Will shew how much you Courtiers are mistaken;</l>
            <l>For Parliaments are not of that cheap rate,</l>
            <l>That they will down without a broken Pate;</l>
            <l>And then I doubt you'll find those worthy Lords</l>
            <l>More Braves and Champions with their Tongue than Swords.</l>
            <l>Wherefore, Dread Sir, encline not Royal Ear</l>
            <l>To their Advice, but safer Counsels hear;</l>
            <l>Stay till these Lords have got a Crown to lose,</l>
            <l>And then consult with them which way they'll chuse.</l>
            <l>Will you all hazard for their humours sake,</l>
            <l>Who nothing have to lose, nothing at stake,</l>
            <l>And at one Game your Royal Crown expose,</l>
            <l>To gratifie the foolish Lusts of those,</l>
            <l>Who hardly have Subsistence how to live,</l>
            <l>But what your Crown and Grace to them do's give?</l>
            <l>And one of those (Bag pudding) Gentlemen,</l>
            <l>(Except their Places) would buy nine or ten:</l>
            <l>Then, why, they should thus sl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ght the Gentleman,</l>
            <l>I see no reason, nor think how they can;</l>
            <l>For had no Gentleman done more than Lord,</l>
            <l>I'll boldly say't, you ne'er had been Restor'd.</l>
            <pb n="8" facs="tcp:98643:4"/>
            <l>But why, of Armies now, Great Sir, must we</l>
            <l>(So fond just now) all on the sudden be?</l>
            <l>What faithful Guardians have they been to Pow'rs</l>
            <l>That have employ'd em, that you'd make 'em yours?</l>
            <l>Enough our Age, we need not seek the glory</l>
            <l>Of Armies Faith; in old, or doubtful Story▪</l>
            <l>Your Father 'gainst the <hi>Scots</hi> an Army rear'd,</l>
            <l>But soon, that Army more than <hi>Scot</hi> he fear'd:</l>
            <l>He was in hast to raise them, as we are,</l>
            <l>But to Disband them was far more his care;</l>
            <l>How <hi>Scottish</hi> Army after did betray</l>
            <l>His Trust, and Person both, I need not say.</l>
            <l>Rump Parliament an Army rear'd, and they</l>
            <l>The Parliament that rais'd them, did betray;</l>
            <l>The Lord Protector they set up one hour,</l>
            <l>The next pull'd down the Protectorian pow'r.</l>
            <l>Your Father's Block and Judges the same Troops</l>
            <l>Did guard, some Tongues at Death of both made hoops:</l>
            <l>And will you suffer Armies to beguile,</l>
            <l>And give your Crown and them to cross and pile?</l>
            <l>What if as <hi>Mon<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> should both swear, lie and feign,</l>
            <l>Till he do's both your Trust and Army gain,</l>
            <l>And you believe his Oath, and Faith is true,</l>
            <l>But serves himself instead of serving you.</l>
            <l>Pardon, Great Sir, if Zeal transports my Tongue,</l>
            <l>T'express what your Greatness don't become.</l>
            <l>Expose I can't your Crown, and sacred Throat</l>
            <l>To the false Faith of a common Red-coat.</l>
            <l>Your Law your All do's fence secure from Fears;</l>
            <l>That kept, what trouble needs of Bandileers?</l>
            <l>Consider, Sir, 'tis Law that makes you King,</l>
            <l>The Sword another to the Crown may bring;</l>
            <l>For Force knows no distinction, longest Sword</l>
            <l>Makes Peasant Prince, Lacquey above his Lord.</l>
            <l>If that be all that we must have for Laws.</l>
            <l>Your Will inferior may be to <hi>Jack Straw</hi>'s,</l>
            <l>If greater Force him follow; There's no Right</l>
            <l>Where Law is failing, and for Will Men fight.</l>
            <l>Best man is he alone whose Steel's most strong;</l>
            <l>Where no Law is, there's neither right nor wrong;</l>
            <l>That Fence broke down, and all in common laid,</l>
            <l>Subjects may Prince, and Prince may them invade.</l>
            <l>See, Greatest Sir, how these your Throne lay down,</l>
            <l>Instead of making great your Royal Crown,</l>
            <l>How they divest you of your Majesty;</l>
            <l>For Law destroy'd, you are no more than we▪</l>
            <l>And very vain would be the Plea of Crown.</l>
            <l>When Statute-Laws, and Parliaments are down.</l>
            <l>This Peer proceeded on to shew how vain</l>
            <l>An Holy League would be with <hi>Rome</hi> again,</l>
            <l>And what dishonour 'twould be to our Crowns,</l>
            <l>If unto <hi>France</hi> give cautionary Towns.</l>
            <l>He's interrupted, and bid speak no more,</l>
            <l>By's enraged Majesty, who deeply swore,</l>
            <l>His Tongue had so run o'er, that he'd take</l>
            <l>Such Vengence on him, and example make</l>
            <l>To after Ages▪ all which heard should fear,</l>
            <l>To speak what wou'd displease the Royal Ear;</l>
            <l>And bid the Lord that spoke before, go on,</l>
            <l>And Silence all should keep till he had done;</l>
            <l>Who thus his Speech re'ssum'd. If Lord spake last,</l>
            <l>To interrupt me had not made such hast,</l>
            <l>I soon had done; For I was come, Great Sir,</l>
            <l>T' advise your sending <hi>Dutch</hi> Embassador;</l>
            <l>But much it does concern you whom to trust,</l>
            <l>With this Embassy: for none true, nor just,</l>
            <l>Wise, Stout, or Honourable, nor a Friend,</l>
            <l>Should you in any wise resolve to send,</l>
            <l>Lest any unseen, or unlucky Chance</l>
            <l>Shou'd in this War befal to us, or <hi>France.</hi>
            </l>
            <l>We may that loathed wretch give to the hate</l>
            <l>Of th'Peoples fury, them to satiate.</l>
            <l>And when all's done, that can be done by man,</l>
            <l>Much must be left to chance, do what you can.</l>
            <l>And if you'll make all Christendom your Friend,</l>
            <l>And put to <hi>Dutch-Land</hi>-League an utter end;</l>
            <l>Then surely you may have of Men and Treasure</l>
            <l>Enough of both to execute your Pleasure.</l>
            <l>This Speech being ended, five or six agree,</l>
            <l>
               <hi>France</hi> shall be lov'd, and <hi>Holland</hi> hated be.</l>
            <l>All gone, I wak'd, and wondred what should mean</l>
            <l>All I had heard, methought 'twas more than Dream.</l>
            <l>And if Cabal thus serves us <hi>Englishmen,</hi>
            </l>
            <l>'Tis ten to one but I shall dream again.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb n="9" facs="tcp:98643:4"/>
            <head>The History of <hi>Insipids,</hi> A LAMPOON. 1676.</head>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>1.</head>
               <l>CHast, pious, prudent, C— the Second,</l>
               <l>The Miracle of thy Restauration,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ay like to that of <hi>Quails</hi> be reckon'd</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ain'd on the Israelitick Nation;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he wisht for Blessing from Heav'n sent,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ecame their Curse and Punishment.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <head>2.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he Vertues in thee, C— inherent,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>lthough thy countenance be an odd piece,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>roves thee as true a Gods Vicegerent</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>s e're was <hi>Harry</hi> with the Codpiece:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or Chastity and pious Deeds,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>is Grandsire <hi>Harry,</hi> G— exceeds.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>3.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ur <hi>Romish</hi> Bondage breaker <hi>Harry,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>spoused half a dozen Wives,</l>
               <l>— only one resolv'd to marry,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>od other Mens he never —</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>et hath he Sons and Daughters more,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>han e're had <hi>Harry</hi> by threescore.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>4.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ever was such a Faiths Defender,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e like a politick Prince, and pious,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ives liberty to Conscience render,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nd doth to no Religion tye us.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ews, Christians, Turks, Papists,</hi> he'll please us,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ith <hi>Moses, Mahomet,</hi> or <hi>J</hi>—</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <head>5.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> all Affairs of Church or State,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e very zealous is, and able,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>evout at Prayers, and sits up late</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t the Cabal and Council Table.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>is very Dog at Council-Board,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ts grave and wise, as any Lord.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="6">
               <head>6.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>et C—his Policy no Man flout,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he wisest Kings have all some Folly,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or let his Piety any doubt;</l>
               <l>— like a Sovereign wise and holy,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ake young Men Judges of the Bench,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nd B—some that love a Wench.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="7">
               <head>7.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>is Fathers Foes he doth reward,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>reserving those that cut off's Head:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ld Cavaliers the Crown's best Guard,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e lets them starve for want of Bread.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ever was any King endow'd</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ith so much Grace and Gratitude.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="8">
               <head>8.</head>
               <l>
                  <hi>Blood,</hi> that wears Treason in his Face,</l>
               <l>Villain compleat, in Parsons Gown,</l>
               <l>How much is he at Court in Grace</l>
               <l>For stealing <hi>Ormond,</hi> and the Crown?</l>
               <l>Since Loyalty do's no Man good,</l>
               <l>Let's steal the King and out-do <hi>Blood.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="9">
               <head>9.</head>
               <l>A Parliament of Knaves and Sots,</l>
               <l>Members by Name, you must not mention,</l>
               <l>He keeps in Pay, and buys their Votes,</l>
               <l>Here with a Place, there with a Pension.</l>
               <l>When to give Mony he can't cologue 'um,</l>
               <l>He doth with Scorn prorogue, prorogue 'um.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="10">
               <head>10.</head>
               <l>But they long since by too much giving,</l>
               <l>Undid, betray'd, and sold the Nation;</l>
               <l>Making their Memberships a Living,</l>
               <l>Better than e're was Sequestration.</l>
               <l>God give thee, C— a Resolution</l>
               <l>To damn the Knaves by Dissolution.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="11">
               <head>11.</head>
               <l>Fame is not grounded on Success,</l>
               <l>Though Victories were <hi>Caesars</hi> Glory;</l>
               <l>Lost Battels make not <hi>Pompey</hi> less,</l>
               <l>But left them stiled great in Story.</l>
               <l>Malitious Fate doth oft devise</l>
               <l>To beat the Brave and fool the Wise.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="12">
               <head>12.</head>
               <l>C— in the first <hi>Dutch</hi> War stood fair,</l>
               <l>To have been Sovereign of the Deep;</l>
               <l>When <hi>Opdam</hi> blew up in the Air,</l>
               <l>Had not his Highness gone to sleep.</l>
               <l>Our Fleet slack'd Sails, fearing his waking,</l>
               <l>The <hi>Dutch</hi> else had been in sad taking.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="13">
               <head>13.</head>
               <l>The <hi>Bergen</hi> Business was well laid,</l>
               <l>Though we paid dear for that Design:</l>
               <l>Had we not three days parling staid,</l>
               <l>The <hi>Dutch</hi> Fleet there, C— had been thine.</l>
               <l>Though the false <hi>Dane</hi> agree'd to sell 'um,</l>
               <l>He cheated us, and saved <hi>Skellum.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="14">
               <head>14.</head>
               <l>Had not C— sweetly choos'd the States,</l>
               <l>By <hi>Bergen</hi> Baffle grown more wise.</l>
               <l>And made them Shit as small as Ratts,</l>
               <l>By their rich <hi>Smyrna</hi> Fleets Surprize.</l>
               <l>Had haughty <hi>Holms</hi> but call'd in <hi>Spragg,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Hands had been put into a Bag.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="15">
               <head>15.</head>
               <l>Mists, Storms, short Victuals, adverse Winds,</l>
               <l>And once the Navies wise Division,</l>
               <l>Defeated C— his best Designs,</l>
               <l>Till he became his Foes Derision.</l>
               <l>But he had swing'd the <hi>Dutch</hi> at <hi>Chattam,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Had he had Ships but to come at 'um.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="16">
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:98643:5"/>
               <head>16.</head>
               <l>Our <hi>Blackheath</hi> Host without dispute,</l>
               <l>Rais'd, (put on Board, why, no Man knows)</l>
               <l>Must C— have rendred absolute,</l>
               <l>Over his Subjects or his Foes.</l>
               <l>Has not the <hi>French</hi> King made us Fools,</l>
               <l>By taking <hi>Maestricht</hi> with our Tools?</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="17">
               <head>17.</head>
               <l>But C— what could thy Policy be,</l>
               <l>To run so many sad Disasters;</l>
               <l>To join thy Fleet with false <hi>D' Etrees,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To make the <hi>French</hi> of <hi>Holland</hi> Masters?</l>
               <l>Was't <hi>Carewell,</hi> Brother <hi>James,</hi> or <hi>Teague,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That made thee break the Triple League.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="18">
               <head>18.</head>
               <l>Could <hi>Robin Vyner</hi> have foreseen</l>
               <l>The glorious Triumphs of his Master,</l>
               <l>The Wool-Church Statue Gold had been,</l>
               <l>Which now is made of Alabaster:</l>
               <l>But wise Men think had it been Wood,</l>
               <l>Twere for a Bankrupt K— too good.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="19">
               <head>19.</head>
               <l>Those that the Fabrick well consider,</l>
               <l>Do of it diversly discourse;</l>
               <l>Some pass their Censure of the Rider,</l>
               <l>Others their Judgment of the Horse:</l>
               <l>Most say the <hi>Steed's</hi> a goodly thing,</l>
               <l>But all agree 'tis a Lewd K—</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="20">
               <head>20.</head>
               <l>By the Lord Mayor and his grave Coxcombs,</l>
               <l>Free-man of <hi>London</hi> C— is made;</l>
               <l>Then to <hi>Whitehall</hi> a Rich Gold Box comes,</l>
               <l>Which was bestow'd on the <hi>French</hi> Jade.</l>
               <l>But wonder not it should be so, Sirs,</l>
               <l>When Monarchs rank themselves with Grocers.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="21">
               <head>21.</head>
               <l>Cringe, scrape, no more, ye City Fopps,</l>
               <l>Leave off your Feasting and fine Speeches,</l>
               <l>Beat up your Drums, shut up your Shops,</l>
               <l>The Courtiers then will kiss your Breeches.</l>
               <l>Arm'd, tell the Popish Duke that Rules,</l>
               <l>You'r Free-born Subjects, not <hi>French</hi> Mules.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="22">
               <head>22.</head>
               <l>New Upstarts, Pimps, Bastards, Whores,</l>
               <l>That Locust like devour the Land,</l>
               <l>By shutting up the Exchequer Doors,</l>
               <l>When thither our Mony was trapan'd,</l>
               <l>Have rendred C— his Restauration,</l>
               <l>But a small Blessing to the Nation.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="23">
               <head>23.</head>
               <l>Then C— beware of thy Brother <hi>Y</hi>—</l>
               <l>Who to thy Government gives Law;</l>
               <l>If once we fall to the old Sport,</l>
               <l>You must again both to <hi>Breda:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Where Spight of all that would restore you,</l>
               <l>Grown wise by wrongs, we shall abhor you.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="24">
               <head>24.</head>
               <l>If of all Christian Blood the Guilt</l>
               <l>Cry loud for Vengeance unto Heaven;</l>
               <l>That Sea by Treacherous <hi>Lewis</hi> spilt,</l>
               <l>Can never be by God forgiven.</l>
               <l>Worse Scourge unto his Subjects, Lord,</l>
               <l>Than Pestilence, Famine, Fire or Sword.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="25">
               <head>25.</head>
               <l>That false rapacious Wolf of <hi>France,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The Scourge of <hi>Europe,</hi> and its Curse,</l>
               <l>Who at his Subjects cry, does Dance,</l>
               <l>And study how to make them worse.</l>
               <l>To say such Kings, Lord, rule by thee,</l>
               <l>Were most prodigious Blasphemy.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="26">
               <head>26.</head>
               <l>Such know no Law but their own Lust,</l>
               <l>Their Subjects Substance, and their Blood</l>
               <l>They count it Tribute, due and just,</l>
               <l>Still spent, and spilt, for Subjects good.</l>
               <l>If such Kings are by God appointed,</l>
               <l>The D— may be the L— Anointed.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="27">
               <head>27.</head>
               <l>Such Kings curst be the Power and Name,</l>
               <l>Let all the World henceforth abhor 'um;</l>
               <l>Monsters which Knaves Sacred proclaim,</l>
               <l>And then like Slaves fall down before 'um.</l>
               <l>What can there be in Kings Divine?</l>
               <l>The most are Wolves, Goats, Sheep, or Swine.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="28">
               <head>28.</head>
               <l>Then Farewel Sacred Majesty,</l>
               <l>Let's pull all Brutish Tyrants down;</l>
               <l>When Men are born, and still live free,</l>
               <l>Here ev'ry Head doth wear a Crown.</l>
               <l>Mankind like miserable Froggs,</l>
               <l>Prove wretched, king'd by Storks and Loggs.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>STAFFORDS GHOST February <hi>1680/1.</hi>
            </head>
            <l>IS this the Heav'nly Crown? Are these the Joys</l>
            <l>Which bellowing Priests did promise with such nois<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
            </l>
            <l>Charming my Fears with such lewd Words as these,</l>
            <l>A Saint, A Martyr, Bliss, Eternal Ease?</l>
            <l>Such promised Glories were for meaner Deeds.</l>
            <l>He's trebly blest by whom our Monarch bleeds.</l>
            <l>Curs'd Priests did me with other Fools delude,</l>
            <l>Brib'd with their Gifts of the Beatitude.</l>
            <l>Had I that Life so unadvis'dly lost,</l>
            <l>'Tis not your fawning Jesuitish Host,</l>
            <l>Should e're prevail on my misguided sence,</l>
            <l>To smother Guilt with Vows of Innocence:</l>
            <l>Nor thou, false Friend, as false to me or more,</l>
            <l>Then all thy Oaths for <hi>Coleman</hi>'s Life before;</l>
            <pb n="11" facs="tcp:98643:5"/>
            <l>With thy true Catholick protesting Br<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ath,</l>
            <l>Should'st e're betray me to a perjur'd Death.</l>
            <l>Blinded with Zeal, what, did we once admire</l>
            <l>A Sulph'rous Soul, by Jesuits set on Fire;</l>
            <l>A Headstrong, Stupid, Rash Bigotted P—</l>
            <l>Declar'd the open Enemy to Sence.</l>
            <l>Weak are the Sacred Ties that should attend</l>
            <l>The Name of Sov'raign, Brother, and of Friend;</l>
            <l>This Pious <hi>Samson</hi> would with Joy o're throw</l>
            <l>The Universe, and perish by the Blow;</l>
            <l>His Plots, tho known, yet will he ne're give o're,</l>
            <l>But still Intreagues with his dear <hi>Babel</hi> Whore:</l>
            <l>So much infected by that Fatal Bitch,</l>
            <l>He's all broke out in Scabby Zeal and Itch.</l>
            <l>Could we distinctly view his Tainted Soul</l>
            <l>That All the Relicks of <hi>S</hi>— were small,</l>
            <l>Compar'd with th' Scarrs of his P— Spiritual;</l>
            <l>'Tis not the pow'rful Force of <hi>Jordan</hi>'s Streams,</l>
            <l>Nor his dear Purgatorys cleansing Flames,</l>
            <l>Can e're remove from his polluted Soul,</l>
            <l>The least Remains of a Disease so foul:</l>
            <l>You'll say, 'tis hard that such a one as he</l>
            <l>Should be depriv'd of <hi>Naamans</hi> Remedy;</l>
            <l>But there's distinction to be made, I hope,</l>
            <l>'Twixt those that worship <hi>Rimmon</hi> and the <hi>Pope.</hi>
            </l>
            <l>Amends for my intended Crimes I make,</l>
            <l>If <hi>Charles</hi> from his Lethargick Sleep I wake,</l>
            <l>But such a Dose of Opiats they have given</l>
            <l>To Rouse him were a Miracle for Heaven;</l>
            <l>I hope, tho when he hears what I can tell,</l>
            <l>Success may Crown my Embassy from Hell.</l>
            <l>I'll boldly name those that pursue his Life,</l>
            <l>And 'mongst his Subjects fester endless Strife;</l>
            <l>Their Friends and their Advisers I'll reveal,</l>
            <l>Those Holy Men that touch'd with pious Zeal</l>
            <l>Are such Well-wishers to the Common Weal.</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Y</hi>— most Belov'd, and boldest Friend is he,</l>
            <l>Who knows he must Succeed by <hi>Gadbury;</hi>
            </l>
            <l>Yet some with wonder are surpriz'd to find</l>
            <l>That in the Loyal Ague of his Mind,</l>
            <l>His hot Fit comes in such a proper time,</l>
            <l>Whose cold one thought the Covenant no Crime.</l>
            <l>The next a Slave to his Ambitious Pride,</l>
            <l>Must be the chief, tho of the falling side.</l>
            <l>This Hot-brain'd <hi>Machiavel</hi> once vainly strove,</l>
            <l>For what he ne're can hope, the Peoples Love.</l>
            <l>But foil'd he flies for Refug<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> to the Throne,</l>
            <l>Trusting to th' Bladders of his Wit alone,</l>
            <l>Without one Honest Thought to fix them on.</l>
            <l>The Third a Wrack of the divided Chits,</l>
            <l>Better than Jilting Whore he Counterfeits;</l>
            <l>But not his treach'rous Eyes dissolv'd in Tears,</l>
            <l>Nor the false Vizard his Ambition wears,</l>
            <l>Can blind the World, or hide what must be seen,</l>
            <l>His Practices with <hi>J</hi>— and <hi>Maz—n.</hi>
            </l>
            <l>Vote on, poor Fools! ye Commons vent your Spleen;</l>
            <l>Sure <hi>France</hi> and <hi>Y</hi>— are a sufficient Screen:</l>
            <l>A Tax at Home 's a Project Old and Dull.</l>
            <l>He'll find new ways to keep the Coffers Full;</l>
            <l>The <hi>French</hi> shall some of our fled Gold restore,</l>
            <l>They suck like Leeches, but they ruine more</l>
            <l>When they Spue back part of th' infected Ore.</l>
            <l>'Tis his Contrivance too, by Change of Air,</l>
            <l>To ease our Monarch of his Fears and Care.</l>
            <l>They jointly toil to make thy Burden light,</l>
            <l>Knowing that Quiet is thy chief Delight,</l>
            <l>They therefore haste and hurry thee to fight.</l>
            <l>No Matter <hi>C</hi>— thy Enemies they'l fright,</l>
            <l>One Stamps, one Talks, one Weeps thy Foes to flight,</l>
            <l>I come (dread Lord) from the dark Shades below</l>
            <l>To give thee timely Notice of the Blow.</l>
            <l>Which thou may'st yet prevent; think well of those</l>
            <l>whom now (mistaken) you believe your Foes.</l>
            <l>They who against your Will wou'd fix your Crown,</l>
            <l>Giving your Riches, Happiness, Renown:</l>
            <l>Which <hi>Metamorphose</hi> should accepted be,</l>
            <l>Because redeem'd from Want and Infamy.</l>
            <l>(Observe poor Wanderer, how thou walkst alone,</l>
            <l>Might is the <hi>Atlas</hi> that supports thy Throne.)</l>
            <l>Hast to comply, defer it not too long,</l>
            <l>Thou can'st not stem a Current that's so strong.</l>
            <l>Trust to th' Affections of thy <hi>Britains</hi> bold,</l>
            <l>Give them but leave thy Honour to uphold;</l>
            <l>Tho <hi>Bessus,</hi> yet a <hi>Caesar</hi> thou may'st be,</l>
            <l>Opprest with Trophies of their Victory.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>On the <hi>D—ss</hi> of <hi>P—th</hi>'s PICTURE, <hi>Sept.</hi> 1682.</head>
            <l>VVHo can on this Picture look,</l>
            <l>And not strait be Wonder strook,</l>
            <l>That such a peaking doudy Thing</l>
            <l>Should make a Beggar of a King?</l>
            <l>Three Happy Nations turn to Tears,</l>
            <l>And all their former Love to Fears;</l>
            <l>Ruine the Great, and raise the Small,</l>
            <l>Yet will by turns betray 'um All.</l>
            <l>Lowly Born and meanly Bred,</l>
            <l>Yet of this Nation is the Head:</l>
            <l>For half <hi>Whitehall</hi> make her their Court,</l>
            <l>Tho th' other half make her their Sport.</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Monmouth</hi>'s Tamer, <hi>Jeffery</hi>'s Advance,</l>
            <l>Foe to <hi>England,</hi> Spye for <hi>France;</hi>
            </l>
            <l>False and Foolish, Proud and Bold,</l>
            <l>Ugly, as you see, and Old:</l>
            <l>In a word, her mighty Grace</l>
            <l>Is Whore in all things but her Face.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="song">
            <pb n="12" facs="tcp:98643:6"/>
            <head>A New Song OF THE TIMES, 1683.</head>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>1.</head>
               <l>T'were folly for Ever</l>
               <l>The Whiggs to Endeavour</l>
               <l>Disowning their Plots, when all the World knows 'um</l>
               <l>Did they not fix</l>
               <l>On a Council of Six,</l>
               <l>Appointed to Govern tho no Body Chose 'um.</l>
               <l>They that bore sway,</l>
               <l>Knew not one would Obey</l>
               <l>Did <hi>Trincalo</hi> make such a ridiculous pother;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Monmouth</hi>'s the head,</l>
               <l>To strike Monarchy dead,</l>
               <l>They chose themselves Vice-Roys all o're one another.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <head>2.</head>
               <l>Was't not a damn'd thing</l>
               <l>For <hi>Russel</hi> and <hi>Hambden,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To serve all the projects of Hot-headed <hi>Tony;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But much more untoward</l>
               <l>To appoint my Lord <hi>H</hi>—</l>
               <l>Of his own Purse and Credit to raise Men and Money.</l>
               <l>That at <hi>Knightsbridge</hi> did hide</l>
               <l>Those brisk Boys unspy'd</l>
               <l>Who at <hi>Shaftsbury</hi>'s Whistle were ready to follow;</l>
               <l>And when Aid he should bring,</l>
               <l>Like a true <hi>Brandford</hi> King,</l>
               <l>Was here with a Whoop and gone with a hollow.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>3.</head>
               <l>
                  <hi>Algernoon Sidney,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Of Common-Wealth Kidney,</l>
               <l>Compos'd a damn'd Libell (ay marry was it)</l>
               <l>Writ to occasion</l>
               <l>Ill Blood in the Nation,</l>
               <l>And therefore dispers'd it all over his Closet:</l>
               <l>It was not the Writing</l>
               <l>Was prov'd or Indicting;</l>
               <l>Tho' he urg'd Statutes, what was it but fooling,</l>
               <l>Since a new Trust is</l>
               <l>Plac'd in the Chief Justice,</l>
               <l>To damn Law and Reason too by Over-ruling.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>4.</head>
               <l>What if a Traytor,</l>
               <l>In spite of the State Sir,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hould cut his own Throat from one Ear to the other?</l>
               <l>Shall then a new freak</l>
               <l>Make <hi>Braddon</hi> and <hi>Speak</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o be more concern'd than his Wife or his Brother?</l>
               <l>A Rasor all Bloody</l>
               <l>Thrown out of a Studdy</l>
               <l>Is Evidence strong of his desperate guilt, Sir;</l>
               <l>So <hi>Godfrey,</hi> when dead,</l>
               <l>Full of horror and dread,</l>
               <l>Run his Sword thro' his Body up to the Hilt Sir.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <head>5.</head>
               <l>Who can think the case hard</l>
               <l>Of Sir <hi>Patience Ward,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That lov'd his just Rights more than those of his Highness.</l>
               <l>Oh Disloyal Ears,</l>
               <l>As on Record appears,</l>
               <l>Not to hear when to do the Papists a kindness.</l>
               <l>An Old doting Citt,</l>
               <l>With his <hi>Elizabeth</hi> Wit,</l>
               <l>Against the French Mode for freedom to hope on</l>
               <l>His Ears that told lies</l>
               <l>Were less dull than his Eyes,</l>
               <l>For both them were shut when all others were open.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="6">
               <head>6.</head>
               <l>All <hi>Europe</hi> together</l>
               <l>Can't shew such a Father</l>
               <l>So tenderly nice of his Sons Reputation,</l>
               <l>As our good King is</l>
               <l>To labour to bring his,</l>
               <l>By tricks to subscribe to a shamm Declaration.</l>
               <l>'Twas very good reason</l>
               <l>To pardon his Treason,</l>
               <l>To Obey (not his own, but) his Brothers Command, Sir;</l>
               <l>To merit whose grace,</l>
               <l>He must in the first place</l>
               <l>Confess he's dishonest under his hand Sir.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="7">
               <head>7.</head>
               <l>Since Fate the Court blesses,</l>
               <l>With daily Successes,</l>
               <l>And giving up Charters go round for a frolick,</l>
               <l>Whilst our D—<hi>Nero,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The Churches blind Hero</l>
               <l>By Murder is planting his Faith Apostolick,</l>
               <l>Our Modern Sages,</l>
               <l>More Wise than past Ages,</l>
               <l>Think ours to Establish by Popish Successors;</l>
               <l>Queen <hi>Bess</hi> never thought it,</l>
               <l>And <hi>Cecil</hi> forgot it,</l>
               <l>But 'tis lately found out by our prudent Addressors.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>
               <hi>Enter</hi> Olivers Porter, Fidler, <hi>and</hi> Poet <hi>In</hi> BEDLAM.</head>
            <stage>The Scene adorned with several of the Poets own Flowers.</stage>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>O Glory! Glory! who are these Appear?</l>
               <l>My Fellow-Servants, Poet, Fidler here?</l>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:98643:6"/>
               <l>Old <hi>Hodge</hi> the Constant, <hi>Johnny</hi> the Sincere.</l>
               <l>Who sent you hither? and pray tell me why</l>
               <l>'An horrid-silence does Invade mine Eye?</l>
               <l>'While not one sound of Voice from you I spy</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>I come to let thee know, the Time is now</l>
               <l>To turn and fawn, and slatter as we do,</l>
               <l>And follow that which does too fast pursue:</l>
               <l>Be wise, neglect your Interest now no more;</l>
               <l>Interest! the Prince we serve, God we adore.</l>
               <l>I for the Royal Martyr first declar'd;</l>
               <l>But, e're his head was off, I was prepar'd</l>
               <l>To own the Rump, and for that Cause did Rhime;</l>
               <l>But those kick'd out, next Moment turn'd to him</l>
               <l>Who routed them: Call'd him my Sovereign,</l>
               <l>And prais'd his opening of the Kingly Vein.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>I by my Low'ring Planets was accurst</l>
               <l>To be for barren Loyalty at first;</l>
               <l>But when to <hi>Nolls,</hi> our <hi>Charles</hi>'s fate gave place,</l>
               <l>I could abjure the Unhappy Royal Race:</l>
               <l>To <hi>Noll</hi> I all my fingers skill did show,</l>
               <l>And charm'd his Highness with my nimble Bow.</l>
               <l>Besides, I serv'd him as a faithfull spy,</l>
               <l>And did decoy the Cavalierish Frye;</l>
               <l>Gold from his Bounteous Highness charm'd my Eyes,</l>
               <l>My old Whore <hi>Balt Gl—ss</hi> could ne're suffice</l>
               <l>For the Expence and Equipage of spies.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>Come joyn with us to make our Party strong,</l>
               <l>And you can never be in <hi>Bedlam</hi> long.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>Were you yet Madder you might serve the state,</l>
               <l>And be concern'd in things of greatest weight.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>For (as the <hi>Turks</hi> their <hi>Santons</hi>) we adore</l>
               <l>The Fools and Madmen, and their aid implore:</l>
               <l>They're such who share my Panegyrick Verse.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>To such I write, not to Philosophers.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>Such frequent turns should you to <hi>Bedlam</hi> bring</l>
               <l>From <hi>Rump</hi> to <hi>Cromwell, Cromwell</hi> to the King;</l>
               <l>Then to your Idol Church, next to the Pope,</l>
               <l>Which may one day prefer you to the Rope:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> amongst Madmen am confin'd 'tis true,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ut I have more solidity than you.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>A Windmill is not fickle; for we find</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hat it is always constant to the Wind:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> never change; I'm still to Interest true;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he Conquerour ever does my Muse subdue;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>od with whatever Tossing she shall meet,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e, like a Cat, shall light upon her feet.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>How long did I write for the <hi>English</hi> Church,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t now think sit to leave her in the lurch:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ke <hi>Will-o'th'-Wispe</hi> th' Inferiour Clergy I</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>d into Quagmires, where I let them lie;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>me into Boggs and Ditches I have cast,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>here let them slounder what they will, they're fast:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> far Crape-Gown is plung'd into the mire,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> is not possible it should retire.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>My Spirit boils within my troubled Breast,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ese Rogues are come to interrupt my rest,</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>When the Exalted <hi>Whiggs</hi> were in their Pride</l>
               <l>I spent my Oyl and Labour on their side.</l>
               <l>Wrote a <hi>Whigg</hi> Play, and <hi>Shaftsbury</hi> out-ran;</l>
               <l>For all my Maxims were Republican;</l>
               <l>For the Excluding-Bill I did declare,</l>
               <l>Libell'd and Rail'd, and did not Monarch spare:</l>
               <l>When they began to droop I fac'd about,</l>
               <l>And with my Pen I damn'd the <hi>Whiggish</hi> rout.</l>
               <l>Nay every turn before-hand I can find,</l>
               <l>As your sagacious Hog foresees the Wind.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>You nimbly turn to that which does prevail,</l>
               <l>No Seaman e're could sooner shift his Sail.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>Like a true Renegado still I maul</l>
               <l>The party I forsook with utmost gall.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>So I ere long shall damn the Heretick Souls</l>
               <l>Of my old Comrade Coffee-Priests near <hi>Pauls.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Spies upon all their Pulpits I maintain,</l>
               <l>And if of <hi>Rome,</hi> or Slavery they complain,</l>
               <l>Or for their own against our Church they Preach;</l>
               <l>I War as if they did Sedition Teach:</l>
               <l>I brand the Person with most Venemous Lies</l>
               <l>If I want Truth, Invention still supplies.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>But a reserve I kept for <hi>Monmouth</hi> still</l>
               <l>Should he prevail, I with such equal skill</l>
               <l>With Satyr-mingled praise he could not take it Ill.</l>
               <l>And had that Prince Victorious been at <hi>Lime,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>I the Black-Box had justified in Rhime.</l>
               <l>I was prepar'd to praise or to abhor him,</l>
               <l>Satyr I had and Panegyrick for him.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <stage>[<hi>Porter</hi> aside.]</stage>
               <l>Oh seed of <hi>Locusts,</hi> the Infernal Lake!</l>
               <l>You'l cause my Anger and I'le make you quake.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>Long my sly pen serv'd <hi>Rome,</hi> and I atchiev'd</l>
               <l>Ample Rewards, whole sholes of Priests deceiv'd.</l>
               <l>I wrought with such Imperceptible Tools,</l>
               <l>That I of heaps of Guineas gull'd those Fools;</l>
               <l>The only Bubbles in the World they be,</l>
               <l>Who, to their cost, must feel before they see.</l>
               <l>In publick yet the <hi>English</hi> Church I own,</l>
               <l>Tho' I am subtilly Writing of it down;</l>
               <l>For yet it is not time I should declare</l>
               <l>Lest Fools, to whom I write, should be aware.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>Men best themselves 'gainst open foes defend,</l>
               <l>But perish surely by a seeming Friend.</l>
               <l>One Son turn'd me, I turn'd the other two;</l>
               <l>But had not an Indulgence, Sir, like you;</l>
               <l>I felt my Purse insensibly consume</l>
               <l>Till I had openly declar'd for <hi>Rome.</hi>
               </l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>Now fellow Servant pray at length be wise,</l>
               <l>And follow our Example and Advice.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>What! turn to <hi>Rome,</hi> who did our City burn?</l>
               <l>And wou'd our Ancient Government o'return?</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>Hold! Is not the Inscription blotted out?</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>Therefore who burnt the City none need doubt.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>It was Almighty Fire from Heav'n came down</l>
               <l>To punish the Rebellious stiff-neck'd Town;</l>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:98643:7"/>
               <l>All which had perish'd in devouring flames</l>
               <l>Tho on the fire y<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>had emptied all the <hi>Thames:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Had all its Waves been on the Houses tost,</l>
               <l>It had but basted them as they did rost;</l>
               <l>But Heaven a Chrystal Pyramid did take,</l>
               <l>Of that a broad Extinguisher did make</l>
               <l>In Firmamental Waters dipt above,</l>
               <l>To Hood the Flames which to their Quarry strove.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>A Pyramid Extinguisher to Hood!</l>
               <l>Tis Nonsense never to be understood.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>What, you believe the Plot of Varlet <hi>Oates?</hi>
               </l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>Ten Proclamations and Four Senates Votes.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>That <hi>Godfreys</hi> Life was by the Papists sped?</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>Oh, No! He kill'd himself when he was dead.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>To Jesuits dying you will Credit give.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>Yes! full as much as all the while they live.</l>
               <l>But dying Protestants I'll not believe,</l>
               <l>For they allow of neat Equivocation,</l>
               <l>And of flat Lies, with Mental Reservation.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>Hark <hi>Hodge:</hi> To gain him we in vain contend,</l>
               <l>Our Fellow Servant is a Wagg, dear Friend.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>I'le try him farther; for his Parts are such,</l>
               <l>To bring him o're must needs avail us much,</l>
               <l>Who are for <hi>Rome</hi> and <hi>France</hi> 'gainst th' <hi>English</hi> and the <hi>Dutch.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Come Fellow Servant, you belief our Plot</l>
               <l>Of <hi>Russel, Hamden, Sydney,</hi> and what not?</l>
               <l>Of <hi>B—d, Walcot, Bow-steeple</hi> and the <hi>Rye.</hi>
               </l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>For <hi>R—l</hi> would, but <hi>Hambden</hi> wou'd not Lie,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Rumbald</hi> and <hi>Walcot</hi> too did both deny</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Ayloff</hi> to boot; but Cowards are not brave;</l>
               <l>For Fear's a Passion which all Cowards have:</l>
               <l>Yet to the Plot I firm belief afford,</l>
               <l>Of th' Evidence I credit not one word.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>Can you distrust what <hi>Gr—y</hi> and <hi>Escr—k</hi> say?</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>What! two such Excellent Moral Men as they!</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>Others there are swore home as Men cou'd do.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>Who for their Lives must swear, swear home 'tis true.</l>
               <l>Against the Popish Crew none ever swore</l>
               <l>But a full Pardon he obtain'd before;</l>
               <l>These Swearers are like Cormorants, for they,</l>
               <l>On <hi>Whiggs</hi> with ropes about their gullets prey.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>What then? will you not be to Interest true?</l>
               <l>We both are of the same belief with you;</l>
               <l>But we know better what we have to do.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>
                  <hi>Porter</hi> aside.</speaker>
               <l>Did ever Hell send such a brace of Knaves;</l>
               <l>Such abject Cowards, Mercenary Slaves!</l>
            </sp>
            <stage>Exit frowning.</stage>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>His looks are wild, his fiery Eye-balls roul</l>
               <l>A Raging Tempest's labouring in his Soul.</l>
               <l>Let's prudently retire.</l>
            </sp>
            <stage>Porter <hi>Re-enters with a great Bible given him by</hi> Nell Gwin.</stage>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>You sneaking Rogues</l>
               <l>would you be gone?</l>
               <l>Here's that shall knock both <stage>
                     <hi>He knocks them dow<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> with the Bible, and stamps upon them, they get up.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </l>
               <l>you and Popery down.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>Rash! Man for this I full revenge will take,</l>
               <l>And set our Evidence upon your back,</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>Audacious Fool, how dare you tempt your sate<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>Provoking me a Pillar of the State,</l>
               <l>Who with my Pen alone have turn'd the Scale.</l>
               <l>And made the <hi>Tories</hi> o're the <hi>Whiggs</hi> prevail?</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>Your Pen alone! —</l>
               <l>Can I this Arrogance endure to hear,</l>
               <l>Wou'd you usurp the Garland I should wear?</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>You with your Forty Eight and Forty One,</l>
               <l>With Screws and Antipendiums plagu'd the Town;</l>
               <l>While even the <hi>Whiggs</hi> admir'd my lofty Verses,</l>
               <l>Your Witless Prose did Fodder forty Arses.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>I'le through your Arse touch Honour to t<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> quic<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>And find if you have any by this kick. <stage>
                     <hi>Kicks the</hi> Poe<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </stage>
               </l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>Kick on, old Fool, till you your Toes shall ma<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>I have had several, and can bear them all:</l>
               <l>Besides, I'm us'd to't.—</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>—Hence you Wretched Slaves,</l>
               <l>There is Contagion in such Fools and Knaves.</l>
               <l>I'll wring your Necks off if you ever more</l>
               <l>Presume to set your Feet within this door:</l>
               <l>I'm Chief and have Dominion in this Place.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>I'le spend my gushing Blood upon thy Face</l>
               <l>And if thou dar'st effect thy dire Design</l>
               <l>With my two hands I'le sling my Head at thine.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>Holloa St. <hi>Dennis</hi> have at you.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Johnny.</speaker>
               <l>Murder, Murder! <stage>
                     <hi>He Kicks &amp; beats the<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap> they run roaring out.</hi>
                  </stage>
               </l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Hodge.</speaker>
               <l>Help, Help!</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Porter.</speaker>
               <l>I on these Knaves shall never more compla<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>They have call'd back my wandring sense again.</l>
               <stage>He Pawses and seems come to himself.</stage>
               <l>Of all Mankind happy alone are we,</l>
               <l>From all Ambition, from all Tumults free:</l>
               <l>No Plots nor vile Informers need we fear;</l>
               <l>No Plagues, nor Tortures for Religion here.</l>
               <l>Our Thoughts, nay even our Words are free,</l>
               <l>Not damn'd by Fines, or loss of Liberty;</l>
               <l>None here's Impeach'd by a vile Table spy,</l>
               <l>Who with an <hi>Innuendo</hi> backs his Lye;</l>
               <l>Words and Lampoons we laugh at, and ne're care</l>
               <l>What's said by Men, if Actions they forbear;</l>
               <l>Anger at Words is weakness understood,</l>
               <l>Since none can Ridicule ought that is good;</l>
               <l>Tis Womanish, and springs from Impotence,</l>
               <l>For no great Man at words e're took Offence.</l>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:98643:7"/>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t <hi>Rome,</hi> in all her Glory, words were free;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ast Governments can never Jealous be;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ut when to Tyranny <hi>Rome</hi> did decline,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>eak Emperours with <hi>Delatores</hi> joyn</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o Plague the People, and themselves undo;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or when they're fear'd they must be hated too.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nd whom Men hate with Ruin they'll pursue.</l>
               <l>One Witness and a Circumstance for Facts</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>s not enough; We must prove Overt-Acts.</l>
               <l>Our happy Government makes no Offence</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ut open and Rebellious Violence.</l>
               <l>Which we to quell no standing Army need,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or can Dragoons upon Free quarter feed;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ooted Apostles we have none, that come</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o knock and beat Men to the Church of <hi>Rome;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hen its Butt-end prevails not, Torments will,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or <hi>Lewis</hi> is not yet so Mercifull to kill.</l>
               <l>Here we divided from the troubled World,</l>
               <l>Rest and are into no Confusions hurl'd;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or all our wants does our wise State provide</l>
               <l>Here ev'ry Vacant Place is still supply'd</l>
               <l>With Persons that are duly qualify'd;</l>
               <l>No Favour Raises a Desertless Knave,</l>
               <l>Nor Infamy, nor yet th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Gold he gave.</l>
               <l>How would all Subjects envy us shou'd we</l>
               <l>Publish the Secrets of our Hierarchy,</l>
            </sp>
         </div>
         <div type="dialogue">
            <head>A DIALOGUE BETWEEN Father <hi>Petres</hi> and the <hi>Devil.</hi>
            </head>
            <stage>
               <hi>Father</hi> Petres <hi>to the</hi> Devil.</stage>
            <l>OH! are you come? 'tis more than time,</l>
            <l>Your Tardiness is no small Crime;</l>
            <l>All our Proceeding's at a Stand,</l>
            <l>They've got again the upper hand:</l>
            <l>Yet like true <hi>Jesuit</hi> I have wrought,</l>
            <l>My charge up to the height I sought;</l>
            <l>Both Sence and Reason quite o'rethrown,</l>
            <l>For those we deal with must have none.</l>
            <sp>
               <speaker>The Devil's Answer.</speaker>
               <l>Is this a Conquest to relate,</l>
               <l>Worthy a Jesuitick Pate?</l>
               <l>I have more trouble with you had,</l>
               <l>Than all the Orders I have made;</l>
               <l>Besides, I Joyn'd in the design,</l>
               <l>One whose Fell Malice Equals mine,</l>
               <l>One so ambitiously Inclin'd,</l>
               <l>Of such an uncontrouled mind;</l>
               <l>That let the Gulph be ne're so deep,</l>
               <l>Or Piramid Prodigious steep:</l>
               <l>If in th' Extreams thou canst disclose,</l>
               <l>Any that does their will oppose,</l>
               <l>(Though on just grounds) they meet their Fate,</l>
               <l>In violent and unbounded hate.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Father Petres.</speaker>
               <l>I did not call you to Discourse,</l>
               <l>We must do something now by force;</l>
               <l>Our whole Society is Shamm'd,</l>
               <l>And we in our firs Founder damn'd:</l>
               <l>Did I though to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Soul's Perdition,</l>
               <l>Act things more b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>k than my Commission?</l>
               <l>Gaining belief amongst the Great,</l>
               <l>Who forc'd upon themselves the Cheat,</l>
               <l>While the Good man I kept at th' Oar,</l>
               <l>No Gally slave e're labour'd more,</l>
               <l>Nor durst I let him Pause upon't,</l>
               <l>Lest if he thought, he shou'd recant:</l>
               <l>With Puzling Notions still possest him,</l>
               <l>At once Tormented and Carress'd him,</l>
               <l>Hood-winck'd the Pilot, that shou'd steer us,</l>
               <l>With our Infallible Chimera's.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>The Devil.</speaker>
               <l>Boast not as if you'd Conquest won,</l>
               <l>You've started much, but nothing done;</l>
               <l>Your Order wheresoe're they come,</l>
               <l>Have set whole Kingdoms in a Flame,</l>
               <l>Nor <hi>Hell</hi> nor <hi>Rome</hi> can give you thanks,</l>
               <l>For acting thus a Mad-man's Pranks:</l>
               <l>Did I not always to you Preach,</l>
               <l>The <hi>English</hi> wou'd you over reach?</l>
               <l>They'l be convinc'd ere they believe,</l>
               <l>Not pin their Faith upon your Sleeve:</l>
               <l>Your publick Chappels, have o'rethrown us,</l>
               <l>Our very Proselytes disown us,</l>
               <l>And face about to th' other side,</l>
               <l>Exclaiming 'gainst the <hi>Roman Pride.</hi>
               </l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:98643:8"/>
               <speaker>Father Petres.</speaker>
               <lg>
                  <l>What! do you now complain on me,</l>
                  <l>For over acting Villany?</l>
                  <l>I still consulted you in all,</l>
                  <l>Did daily for your Conduct call;</l>
                  <l>And though 'tis true I nam'd the Saints,</l>
                  <l>Yet 'twas to you I made my plaints;</l>
                  <l>I own about the <hi>French</hi> we fail'd,</l>
                  <l>But in the <hi>Irish</hi> we prevail'd.</l>
                  <l>Propose once more, and I'll obey't,</l>
                  <l>It shall be done if you but say't.</l>
                  <l>You know in such a Holy Juggle,</l>
                  <l>My seared Conscience ner'e did Boggle;</l>
                  <l>We must not Flag, not sit down here,</l>
                  <l>That wou'd declare Remorse or Fear,</l>
                  <l>Which <hi>Jesuits</hi> do more decline,</l>
                  <l>Then e're the <hi>Rechabites</hi> did Wine;</l>
                  <l>But I have something to Impart,</l>
                  <l>Which does oppress my tender Heart,</l>
                  <l>And made me now invoke you hither,</l>
                  <l>Though 'gainst your Principles, to gather</l>
                  <l>The truth of these Important <hi>Queries,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Most needful in this dubious Series.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>First, if it in your Power does lye,</l>
                  <l>Tell me what death I'm doom'd to Die,</l>
                  <l>I dare not hope't must be in Bed,</l>
                  <l>That suits not with the Life I've led;</l>
                  <l>But if I must be Hang'd and Quarter'd,</l>
                  <l>Let me be Cannoniz'd and Martyr'd</l>
                  <l>With holy <hi>Harcourt</hi> and his Fellows,</l>
                  <l>Like them be Sainted at the Gallows.</l>
                  <l>And next I do this Favour Crave,</l>
                  <l>Since I have ever been your Slave,</l>
                  <l>Unfold the Mystick Book of Fate,</l>
                  <l>And Read me <hi>England</hi>'s future State;</l>
                  <l>Who next shall to the Throne Succeed,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>English</hi> or <hi>Italian</hi> Breed.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The <hi>Devil</hi> answering, Laught outright,</l>
                  <l>Wou'd I these Secrets bring to Light,</l>
                  <l>I shou'd not half that Harvest gain,</l>
                  <l>For which I've taken all this pain,</l>
                  <l>Nor wou'd I if I cou'd reveal,</l>
                  <l>That which my Interest bids Conceal;</l>
                  <l>Yet I will Answer thee in Part,</l>
                  <l>Since I've a Title in thy Heart.</l>
                  <l>The first Peculiar is to thee,</l>
                  <l>For which thou need'st not trouble me,</l>
                  <l>'Tis what thy self did Long foresee;</l>
                  <l>Nor is it Reason to believe,</l>
                  <l>Thou should'st the <hi>Mobile</hi> deceive,</l>
                  <l>But whether Martyr, or as Traytor,</l>
                  <l>Thy Ballad will be Truth's Relator.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The Consequence o'th' other draw,</l>
                  <l>By the success of Great <hi>Nassaw.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>This said, the <hi>Devil</hi> left the Father</l>
                  <l>The Meaning of his Words to gather;</l>
                  <l>And Vanish'd from him down the Stairs,</l>
                  <l>While he Proceeded in his Prayers.</l>
               </lg>
            </sp>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>TO THE <hi>Brazen-Head,</hi>
            </head>
            <l>WHat Strepitantious Noise is it that sounds</l>
            <l>From Raised Banks, or from the Lower Grounds?</l>
            <l>From Hollow Caverns, Labyrinths from afar,</l>
            <l>Threatning Confusions of a Dreadful War?</l>
            <l>What Dismal Cries of People in Despair,</l>
            <l>Fill the vast Region of the Troubled Air?</l>
            <l>The Tune of Horror, or of what's as strange,</l>
            <l>That strikes uneven like a World of Change,</l>
            <l>With such a Bold Surprize attacks my Sense,</l>
            <l>Beyond the Power of Counsel or Defence?</l>
            <l>But tho' Blind Fortune rolls her turning Wheel</l>
            <l>With a perpetual Motion, who can feel</l>
            <l>This Surge of Fate, push't on with Fire and Steel?</l>
            <l>You precious Moments of Serener Days!</l>
            <l>When many Victories enlarg'd my Praise,</l>
            <l>And all things ran in a most easie Stream,</l>
            <l>Back unto me their Ocean and Supreme.</l>
            <l>Are you all vanish'd by the sudden Fright,</l>
            <l>And left m' incompass'd wiih a Dismal Night?</l>
            <l>By my own Subjects in suspicion held,</l>
            <l>Murmurings as bad, as if they had Rebell'd?</l>
            <l>You all Con<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rouling Powers of things above!</l>
            <l>Who easier Dictates guide the World by Love!</l>
            <l>Avert th' Impendent Miseries, and show</l>
            <l>Us Earthly Gods, to Govern here below.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>The Answer.</head>
            <l>'TIS well you've thought upon the chiefest Cause,</l>
            <l>Change nothing of Religion nor the Laws.</l>
            <l>Let the Great Monarch this good Motto wear,</l>
            <l>Not only in his Arms but every where.</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Integer Vitae,</hi> is my whole Defence,</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Scelerisque purus,</hi> a most strong Defence;</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Non eget Mauri,</hi> that no Forces need,</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Jaculis nec Arcu,</hi> which Contentions breed:</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Nec venenatis gravida Sagittis</hi>
            </l>
            <l>
               <hi>Pharetra,</hi> to make Loyal his own Cities.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="epitaph">
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:98643:8"/>
            <head>An EPITAPH.</head>
            <l>
               <hi>ALgernon Sidney</hi> fills this Tomb;</l>
            <l>An <hi>Atheist,</hi> by declaiming <hi>Rome:</hi>
            </l>
            <l>A Rebel bold, by striving still</l>
            <l>To keep the Laws above the Will;</l>
            <l>And hindring those would pull them down,</l>
            <l>To leave no limits to a Crown:</l>
            <l>Crimes damn'd by Church and Government,</l>
            <l>Oh! whither must his Soul be sent?</l>
            <l>Of Heaven it must needs despair,</l>
            <l>If that the Pope be Turnkey there;</l>
            <l>And Hell can ne'er it entertain,</l>
            <l>For there is all Tyrannick Reign,</l>
            <l>And Purgatory's such a Pretence</l>
            <l>As ne'er deceiv'd a Man of Sence:</l>
            <l>Where goes it then? Where't ought to go,</l>
            <l>Where Pope and Devil have nought to do.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>A <hi>Stanza</hi> put on <hi>Westminster-hall</hi> Gate.</head>
            <l>VVHen Natures God for our Offences Dy'd,</l>
            <l>Amongst the Twelve, one <hi>Judas</hi> did reside;</l>
            <l>Here's Twelve Assembled for the Nations Peace,</l>
            <l>Amongst which Twelve, Eleven are <hi>Judases:</hi>
            </l>
            <l>One's true to's Trust, but all the rest accord,</l>
            <l>with <hi>Jews</hi> and <hi>Pagans</hi> to betray their Lord.</l>
            <l>What Madness? Slaves, what is't could ye provoke</l>
            <l>To stoop again unto the <hi>Romish</hi> Yoak?</l>
            <l>May ye be Curs'd, and all your Hopes demolish'd,</l>
            <l>And Perish by those Laws ye have Abolish'd.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>On <hi>Easter-day</hi> 87. this was found fixed on the King's Chappel Door.</head>
            <l>VVHen God Almighty had his Palace fram'd,</l>
            <l>That Glorious Shining Place he Heaven Nam'd;</l>
            <l>And when the first Rebellious Angels fell,</l>
            <l>He Doom'd them to a ce<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ain place, call'd Hell.</l>
            <l>Here's Heaven and Hell confirm'd by Sacred Story,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ut yet I ne'er could read of Purgatory,</l>
            <l>That cleansing place which of late years is found,</l>
            <l>
               <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>or sinning Souls to Flux in till they're sound,</l>
            <l>The Priest form'd that for the good <hi>Roman</hi> Race,</l>
            <l>Our Maker never thought of such a place.</l>
            <l>Oh <hi>Rome!</hi> Wee'll own thee for a Learn'd Wise Nation,</l>
            <l>To add a place wanting in Gods Creation.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>To the Prince of <hi>ORANGE,</hi> A Pacquet of Advice, with the Pacquet-boat return'd.</head>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Advice.</speaker>
               <l>THe Year of Wonder now is come,</l>
               <l>A <hi>Jubilee</hi> proclaim at <hi>Rome,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The Church has Regnant made the Crown.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Pacquet.</speaker>
               <l>No more of your admired year,</l>
               <l>No more your <hi>Jubilee's</hi> declare,</l>
               <l>All Trees that Blossom do not bear.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Adv.</speaker>
               <l>
                  <hi>Orange,</hi> lay by your hope of Crowns,</l>
               <l>Give up to <hi>France</hi> your <hi>Belgick</hi> Towns,</l>
               <l>And keep your Fleet out of the Downs.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Pacq.</speaker>
               <l>Wee'll wait for Crowns, not interest quit,</l>
               <l>Till <hi>Lewis</hi> take what he can get,</l>
               <l>And do not you prescribe our Fleet.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Adv.</speaker>
               <l>You boast you've Eighty Men of War,</l>
               <l>Well Rigg'd, and Mann'd, you say they are,</l>
               <l>Such News can't fail of Welcome here.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Pacq.</speaker>
               <l>Well may the sound of Eighty Sail,</l>
               <l>Make <hi>Englands</hi> greatest Courage fail,</l>
               <l>When half the number will prevail.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Adv.</speaker>
               <l>Now we have some upon our Stocks,</l>
               <l>And some are laid up in our Docks,</l>
               <l>When fitted out, will match your Cocks.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Pacq.</speaker>
               <l>Talk not as you would match our Cocks,</l>
               <l>But Launch your few Ships, on the Stocks,</l>
               <l>And if you can secure your Docks.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Adv.</speaker>
               <l>Besides, we have our Men call'd home,</l>
               <l>Which in your Fleet, and Army roam,</l>
               <l>But you, 'tis said, won't let 'em come.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Pacq.</speaker>
               <l>Your Subjects in our Camp and Fleet,</l>
               <l>Whom you with Proclamation greet,</l>
               <l>Will all obey when they think fit.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Adv.</speaker>
               <l>Soldiers and Seamen both we need,</l>
               <l>Old <hi>England</hi>'s quite out of the Breed,</l>
               <l>Feather and Scarf wont do the Deed.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Pacq.</speaker>
               <l>Of Men of Arms never desp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ir,</l>
               <l>The Civiliz'd <hi>Wild-Irish</hi> are</l>
               <l>Couragious, even to Massacre.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:98643:9"/>
               <speaker>Adv.</speaker>
               <l>But if Victorious you'd be made,</l>
               <l>Like us in <hi>Hounslow</hi> Masquerade,</l>
               <l>Advance your Honour and your Trade.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Pacq.</speaker>
               <l>Then take this Council back again,</l>
               <l>Leave off to Mimick in Campaign,</l>
               <l>And fight in earnest on the Main.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Adv.</speaker>
               <l>
                  <hi>Buda</hi> we storm'd, and took with ease,</l>
               <l>Pursue such Grandeur, on the Seas,</l>
               <l>And fight us so when e'er you please.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Pacq,</speaker>
               <l>Your taking <hi>Buda</hi> does declare,</l>
               <l>That you the Glorious Off-spring are,</l>
               <l>Of them who made all <hi>Europe</hi> fear.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Adv.</speaker>
               <l>Such Warlike Actions will at least,</l>
               <l>Inspire each Neighbouring Monarchs Breast,</l>
               <l>Till <hi>Lewis</hi> shall compleat the rest.</l>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Pacq.</speaker>
               <l>Such Camps, such Seiges, and such Shows,</l>
               <l>Makes each small State your power oppose,</l>
               <l>And <hi>Lewis</hi> lead you by the Nose.</l>
            </sp>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>The Story of the <hi>Pot,</hi> and the <hi>Kettle:</hi> As it was told by Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lonel <hi>T—s,</hi> the Night before he Kist the <hi>K—s</hi> Hand.</head>
            <l>As down the Torrent of an angry Flood,</l>
            <l>An Earthen Pot, and a Brass Kettle flow'd;</l>
            <l>The heavy Cauldron sinking, and distrest</l>
            <l>By its own weight, and the fierce Waves opprest,</l>
            <l>Slily bespoke the Lighter Vessels aid,</l>
            <l>And to the Earthen Pitcher friendly said,</l>
            <l>'Come Brother, Why should we divided lose</l>
            <l>'The strength of Union, and our selves expose</l>
            <l>'To the Insults of this poor paultry stream,</l>
            <l>'Which with United Forces we can stemm:</l>
            <l>'Tho' different heretofore have been our parts,</l>
            <l>'The common Danger reconciles our Hearts,</l>
            <l>'Here lend me thy kind Arm to break this Flood.</l>
            <l>The Pitcher this new Friendship understood,</l>
            <l>And made this Answer. 'Tho wish for ease</l>
            <l>'And safety, this alliance does not please,</l>
            <l>'Such different Natures never will agree,</l>
            <l>'Your Constitution is too rough for me;</l>
            <l>'If by the Waves I against you am tost,</l>
            <l>'Or you to me, I equally am lost;</l>
            <l>'And fear more mischief from your hardned side,</l>
            <l>'Than from the Shoar the Billows, or the Tide,</l>
            <l>'I calmer Days, and Ebbing Waves attend,</l>
            <l>'Rather than Buoy you up, and serve your Friend,</l>
            <l>'To perish by the Rigour of my Friend.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>MORAL.</head>
            <l>Learn hence you <hi>Whigs,</hi> and act no more like Fools,</l>
            <l>Nor trust their Friendship, who would make you Tools,</l>
            <l>While empty Praises, and smooth Flatteries serve,</l>
            <l>Pay with feign'd Thanks, what their feign'd Smiles deserve,</l>
            <l>But let not this alliance further pass,</l>
            <l>For know that you are Clay, and they are Brass.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>On <hi>Romes</hi> Pardons, by the E. of <hi>R.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>(1)</head>
               <l>IF <hi>Rome</hi> can pardon Sins, as <hi>Romans</hi> hold,</l>
               <l>And if those Pardons can be bought and sold,</l>
               <l>It were no sin to adore and Worship Gold.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <head>(2)</head>
               <l>If they can purchase Pardons with a Sum,</l>
               <l>For sins they may commit in time to come,</l>
               <l>And for sins past; 'tis very well for <hi>Rome.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>(3)</head>
               <l>At this rate they are happiest that have most,</l>
               <l>They'll purchase Heaven at their own proper cost;</l>
               <l>Alas the poor, all that are so are lost.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>(4)</head>
               <l>Whence came this Knack, or when did it begin,</l>
               <l>What Author have they, or who brought it in:</l>
               <l>Did Christ e'er keep a <hi>Custom-house</hi> for sin.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <head>(5)</head>
               <l>Some Subtil Devil, without more ado,</l>
               <l>Did certainly this sly Invention brew,</l>
               <l>To Gull them of their Souls and Money too.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <opener>To the Tune of <hi>Lilli-burlero,</hi> &amp;c.</opener>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>I.</head>
               <l>THe Pillars of Popery now are blown down,</l>
               <l>One Thousand Six Hundred Eighty and Eight.</l>
               <l>Which has frighted our Monarch away from his Crown,</l>
               <l>One Thousand Six Hundred Eighty and Eight.</l>
               <l>For <hi>Myn Heer</hi> did appear, and they Scampered for fear,</l>
               <l>One thousand Six Hundred Eighty and Eight.</l>
               <l>For <hi>Myn Heer</hi> did appear, and they Scampered for fear,</l>
               <l>One Thousand Six Hundred Eighty and Eight.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:98643:9"/>
               <head>II.</head>
               <l>That Mirror of Mothers and Wonder of Wives,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>With her joy of three Titles are fled for their Lives,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>III.</head>
               <l>
                  <hi>George Jeffries</hi> who boasted his Face was of Brass,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Is now Metamorphos'd into a Welsh Ass,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>IV.</head>
               <l>That Curse of Three Kingdoms, damn'd <hi>Peters</hi> is fled,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Who with <hi>Rome</hi>'s <hi>Ignis Fatuus</hi> our Monarch mis-led,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <head>V.</head>
               <l>Great <hi>Da</hi>— whose presence made Pregnant the Q—</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Now She has withdrawn is no more to be seen,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="6">
               <head>VI.</head>
               <l>Old <hi>Mordant</hi>'s good Service shall doubly be paid,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For his fetching the Q— now his Lordship is slaid,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="7">
               <head>VII.</head>
               <l>That Sink of Sedition the wise Observator,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Shall receive the just Merit that's due to a Traytor,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="8">
               <head>VIII.</head>
               <l>Our Renegade Rhimer the Cudgell'd and lick'd,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For his <hi>Hinde</hi> and his <hi>Panther</hi> shall once more be kick'd,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="9">
               <head>IX.</head>
               <l>Now Old <hi>Obadiah</hi> quits <hi>Ave Maria,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To Sing Lamentations worse than <hi>Jeremiah,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="10">
               <head>X.</head>
               <l>That Wittal and worse who Commanded the Tower,</l>
               <l>One Thous<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nd, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>With that Shrimp of a Souldier sweet <hi>Cecil</hi> did scoure,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="11">
               <head>XI.</head>
               <l>All our Priests are gone back with our Jesuits and Monks,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And our Nunns to their former Profession of Punks,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="12">
               <head>XII.</head>
               <l>Twou'd tire your patience to number the rest,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>You may guess by the Paw at the Bulk of the Beast,</l>
               <l>One Thousand, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="song">
            <head>Popery Pickled: Or, The Jesuits Shooes made of <hi>Running Lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>To the Tune of, <hi>Would you be a Man of Favour.</hi>
            </opener>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>I.</head>
               <l>VVOuld you have a new Play Acted,</l>
               <l>Would you see it just begun;</l>
               <l>Popery is run Distracted,</l>
               <l>And the Priests are all undone:</l>
               <l>Now you'll see their Beads and Crosses,</l>
               <l>All lye prostrate on the ground;</l>
               <l>They're march'd off like Fools and Asses,</l>
               <l>Not one Sculker to be found.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <head>II.</head>
               <l>Would you see the great Ones slying,</l>
               <l>Leaving a Disbanded Court,</l>
               <l>There are Monks and Fryers crying;</l>
               <l>Whether now shall we resort:</l>
               <l>Now the Chapels quite deserted,</l>
               <l>And forsaken like the Crown,</l>
               <l>Popery is now Convicted,</l>
               <l>There's no such thing to be found.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>III.</head>
               <l>Would you see the Priests recanting,</l>
               <l>Now they fear the English Law;</l>
               <l>You shall hear them all a Ranting,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Lero, Lero, Bullen-a-la;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Instead of Reading <hi>Ave Mary,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>In their <hi>Babylonian</hi> Gown:</l>
               <l>You will see the quite contrary,</l>
               <l>Not a Mass-Book to be found.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>IV.</head>
               <l>Would you see the Nest a brooding,</l>
               <l>Which way they their Course shall steer;</l>
               <l>You shall hear them all concluding,</l>
               <l>Any where▪ but staying here;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Jefferies</hi> was prepar'd for Sailing,</l>
               <l>In his long Tarpawling Gown;</l>
               <l>But his Politicks him failing,</l>
               <l>By his Bawling he was found.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <head>V.</head>
               <l>Would you see <hi>Tyrconnel</hi> Sweating,</l>
               <l>For fear of a final Rout;</l>
               <l>Now the Great Convention's Sitting,</l>
               <l>All will soon be brought about:</l>
               <l>He must then forsake his Palace,</l>
               <l>Just as <hi>Peters</hi> did his Gown;</l>
               <l>Like a Coward fly to <hi>Calice,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Where he never may be found.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="6">
               <pb n="20" facs="tcp:98643:10"/>
               <head>VI.</head>
               <l>Would you have the Scene now changed,</l>
               <l>Stay but while this Act is done▪</l>
               <l>And see Father <hi>Peters</hi> Hanged,</l>
               <l>For procuring of a Son:</l>
               <l>See the Chancellor a pleading</l>
               <l>Where he <hi>Russel</hi> Guilty found;</l>
               <l>When he hears his Sentence Reading,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>A</hi> tru Dreamer he'll be found.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="song">
            <head>The Second Part of <hi>Lill-li burlero bullen a-la.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>BY Creist my dear</hi> Morish <hi>vat makes de sho' shad,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>The Herittickes Jear us and mauke me Mad,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, Lero, Lero, Lilli burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, Lero, Lero, Lilli burlero bullen a-la.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Pox take me dear</hi> Tague <hi>but I am in a rage,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Poo' what Impidence is in dish Age?</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Vat if</hi> Dush <hi>shou'd come as dey hope,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>To up hang us for all de Dispence of de Pope;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill— li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Dey shay dat</hi> Tyrconnel<hi>'s a Friend to de Mash,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>For which hees a Trator, a Pimp and an Ass.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Ara' Plague tauke me now I make a Swar,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>I'd to Shent</hi> Ty-burne <hi>will mauke a great Prayer;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>O' I will pray to Shant</hi> Patrickes <hi>Frock,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill— li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Or to</hi> Lorretto<hi>'s Sacred Smocke;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Now a Pox tauke me, what dost dow tink,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>De</hi> English <hi>Confusion to Popery drink,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>And by my Shoul de Mash House pull down,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>While dey were Swearing de Mayor of de Town;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>O' Fait and be, I'll mauke de Decree,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>And Swar by de Chancellor's Modesty;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li bulero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Dat I no longer in</hi> English <hi>will stay,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>For be goad dey will hang us out of de way,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lill — li burlero bullen a-la.</l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Lero, Lero, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>
               <hi>MONMOUTH'S</hi> Rem<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>brance.</head>
            <opener>
               <hi>To the Tune of,</hi> A Begging we will go.</opener>
            <lg>
               <l>VVHat think you of this Age, now</l>
               <l>Popery's in request,</l>
               <l>And He's the Loyall'st Subject</l>
               <l>That slights the Laws the least?</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>When a Torying they go, they go, they go,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>when a Torying they do go.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>What think you of a Whiggish Plot,</l>
               <l>And of their Evidence,</l>
               <l>When all the Laws can't Protect</l>
               <l>The Peoples Innocence?</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>When a Swearing they do go, do go, do go,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>When a Swearing they do go.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>What think you of a General <hi>(G.)</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That did Betray his Lord, <hi>(M.)</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For which he does deserve to Swing</l>
               <l>In <hi>Catch</hi> his Hempen Cord?</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Such a Rogue you ne'er did know, did know, did know,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>such a Rogue you ne'er did know.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:98643:10"/>
               <l>What think you to be Try'd,</l>
               <l>Sir, by Proclamation Laws,</l>
               <l>And Zealously destroy a Prince, <hi>(M.)</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To advance the Popish Cause?</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>And so Mass to make us go, go, go,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>and to Mass to make us go.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>What think you of the Chancellor,</l>
               <l>Be sure he'll do the work;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>stablish a Religion,</l>
               <l>Although it were the Turk?</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>And for Interest he'll do so, do so, do so,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>and for Interest he'll do so.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>In <hi>Lime-street</hi> we said Mass,</l>
               <l>To advance the Popish Cause,</l>
               <l>And set the Mayor to guard it,</l>
               <l>Against his Oath and Laws?</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>To the Court you must bow low, bow low, bow low,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>to the Court you must bow low.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>What think you of proving</l>
               <l>A Popish Army Awful,</l>
               <l>And Bantring the Church with</l>
               <l>Arguments Unlawful?</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>But a Fidling let him go, go, go,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>but a Fidling let him go.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>What would you give to be Sir,</l>
               <l>In Contrite <hi>Prance</hi>'s place,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>en<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>enc'd to a Pillory for</l>
               <l>One small Mite of Grace?</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>When Recanting he did go, did go, did go,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>when Recanting he did go.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>What think you of our <hi>Penal Laws,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That made the Pope to Bow;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>f damn'd Rogues had not betrayed us,</l>
               <l>They had been as <hi>Penal</hi> now?</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>But their Opinions was not so, not so, not so,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>their Opinions was not so.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Yet fear we not that Buggering Dog,</l>
               <l>That sits in Porfrey Chair,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hat swears he is Infallible,</l>
               <l>Cause he's St. <hi>Peter</hi>'s Heir?</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>is a Lye we all do know, do know, do know,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>'tis a Lye, we all do know.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="song">
            <head>A New Song of the <hi>French King's</hi> Fear of an <hi>ORANGE.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>OF a Hectoring <hi>Bully</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Dear Muse, let us sing,</l>
               <l>(Or to speak one's mind fully)</l>
               <l>O'th' <hi>Most Christian</hi> King;</l>
               <l>Who subdues Men by Huffing,</l>
               <l>And Converts Men by Cuffing,</l>
               <l>Yet he fears if an <hi>Orange</hi> approaches too nigh,</l>
               <l>The gay Flower-de-luces will wither and die.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>He's Son to a Chast Queen,</l>
               <l>Tho' (if Authors don't lye,)</l>
               <l>The devout <hi>Mazarine</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Had a Finger i'th' Pye,</l>
               <l>To mould a Church <hi>Hero</hi>
               </l>
               <l>More fierce than a <hi>Nero,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Who yet fears if an <hi>Orange</hi> approaches too nigh,</l>
               <l>His gay Flower-de luces will wither and die.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>While he's scaring his Neighbours</l>
               <l>With swelling <hi>Bravadoes,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>We but laugh at his Vapours</l>
               <l>And <hi>Rhodamantadoes,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Though Monsicur <hi>Le Dauphiu</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Does New Conquests begin,</l>
               <l>Yet they dread if an <hi>Orange</hi> approaches too nigh,</l>
               <l>The gay Flower-de-luces will wither and die.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Prodigious Advance</l>
               <l>That the Prince here has made,</l>
               <l>Makes an Earth-quake in <hi>France</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And great <hi>Lewis</hi> afraid;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>La Chaise</hi> his Address,</l>
               <l>And the Jesuits <hi>Finesse</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Can't hinder an Orange from approaching so nigh,</l>
               <l>That the gay Flower-de-luces will wither and die.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>If a Fury Poetick</l>
               <l>Foreknows things to come,</l>
               <l>I may dare be Prophetick,</l>
               <l>And foretel his just doom,</l>
               <l>Besides, old <hi>Nostredame</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Has Predicted the same,</l>
               <l>That if once the brave <hi>Orange</hi> approaches too nigh,</l>
               <l>The gay Flower-de-luces will wither and die.</l>
            </lg>
            <div n="2" type="part">
               <pb n="22" facs="tcp:98643:11"/>
               <head>The Second Part.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Tis a sport to our Prince</l>
                  <l>To bridle up a King.</l>
                  <l>Tho' the Beast kick and wince</l>
                  <l>His firm Rider to fling,</l>
                  <l>He'll make him Curvet,</l>
                  <l>And so steadily sit,</l>
                  <l>That an <hi>Orange</hi> once planted upon the <hi>French</hi> shore,</l>
                  <l>The gay Flower-de-luces shall flourish no more.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Help, help, some kind Saint,</l>
                  <l>Holy Churches <hi>Two</hi> Sons;</l>
                  <l>Help, thou Church Militant</l>
                  <l>Of Converting Dragoons;</l>
                  <l>Shall <hi>Lewis</hi> Victorious,</l>
                  <l>Shall <hi>Lewis</hi> the Glorious</l>
                  <l>See an <hi>Orange</hi> transplanted upon the <hi>French</hi> shoar,</l>
                  <l>And the gay Flower-de-luces now flourish no more?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Good <hi>Caesar</hi> compound,</l>
                  <l>Do but Trust me once more;</l>
                  <l>If I'm Treacherous found,</l>
                  <l>I'm a Son of a Whore;</l>
                  <l>Let us <hi>En bonne foy</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Our Joyn'd Forces employ,</l>
                  <l>To stave off an <hi>Orange</hi> quite from the <hi>French</hi> shore,</l>
                  <l>Lest the gay Flower-de-luces should flourish no more.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>'Tis a Cursed ill thing,</l>
                  <l>Makes me rave and run mad;</l>
                  <l>If I were not a King</l>
                  <l>I'd my self fight <hi>I-gad;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Besides, Riding will Pain-o</l>
                  <l>My Bag-pipe <hi>in ano;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Must an <hi>Orange</hi> be planted then on the <hi>French</hi> shore,</l>
                  <l>And my gay Flower-de-luces now flourish no more?</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>The wild Worm in my Tail</l>
                  <l>My Vigour all drains,</l>
                  <l>Through its winding <hi>Canale</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>I've voided my Brains;</l>
                  <l>And these damn'd Hereticks</l>
                  <l>Have fool'd my Politicks,</l>
                  <l>For an <hi>Orange</hi> once planted upon the <hi>French</hi> shoar,</l>
                  <l>May gay flower-de-luces will flourish no more.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <head>A Letter to the <hi>Lord Chancellor</hi> Exposing to him the Sentimen<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> of the People, with some Per<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tinent Advice in the Conclusion</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>My Lord,</salute>
            </opener>
            <lg>
               <l>I'D praise your Lordship, but you've had your shire</l>
               <l>Of that before, if not too much by far,</l>
               <l>And now a nobler field for Curses are:</l>
               <l>Yet I'll not Curse, but leave you to the Crowd,</l>
               <l>Who never baulk their rage, but speak aloud;</l>
               <l>In all the Lab'rŷnths of your Crimes, they'll track ye,</l>
               <l>Worse than ten thousand Furies they'll attack ye.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>We talk not here of <hi>Penal Laws</hi> or <hi>Test,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Nor how you King of Terrors in the <hi>West,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>With more than human Cruelty opprest</l>
               <l>Those whose Shades now stab through your Anxious Breast:</l>
               <l>To these I leave you, each with brandish'd Dart,</l>
               <l>Throughly revenge his Quarrel at your Heart.</l>
               <l>For me, I'll only let your Lordship see</l>
               <l>How they resent your chang'd Felicity.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Now may you hear the People as they scowre</l>
               <l>Along, not fear to Damn the Chancellor:</l>
               <l>The Women too, and all the tender Crew</l>
               <l>That us'd to pity all, now laugh at you.</l>
               <l>The very Boys, how do they grin and prate,</l>
               <l>And giggle at the Bills upon your Gate!</l>
               <l>Nay, rather than be frustrate of their hope,</l>
               <l>The Women will contribute for a Rope;</l>
               <l>And those fine Locks that no bless'd Spark might touch,</l>
               <l>On this account <hi>Ketch</hi> may, they love my Lord so much</l>
               <l>Oh for Dispensing now! ah! now's the time!</l>
               <l>Your Eloquence will hardly blanch the Crime;</l>
               <l>And all the turnings of your <hi>Proteus</hi>-wit,</l>
               <l>With all your little tricks, won't help a bit;</l>
               <l>Ev'n that fine Tongue in which your Lordships trust is,</l>
               <l>Now wont, altho sometimes it baffled Justice:</l>
               <l>No <hi>Ignoramus</hi> Juries shall perplex ye,</l>
               <l>But with their <hi>Billa vera</hi>'s now they'll vex ye.</l>
               <l>From their dire Claws no hiding hole you find,</l>
               <l>They speak their own now, not a Parties mind:</l>
               <l>Not now as heretofore, when on the Bench</l>
               <l>Flattery, and Dawbing had such Influence,</l>
               <l>And <hi>Jeffreys</hi> for a Gift would with the Laws dispense.</l>
               <l>But granting all our Laws be out of joynt,</l>
               <l>Why yet they do not fear to gain the point:</l>
               <l>A High Commission may the Cause decide,</l>
               <l>Your Lordship by a Butcher may be try'd,</l>
               <l>When by Commission he is dignify'd,</l>
               <l>His Power you must not doubt, if he be satisfy'd.</l>
               <pb n="23" facs="tcp:98643:11"/>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> this ben't Law; (though we've a President,)</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ou may appeal to the next Parliament:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t these are such damn'd Sticklers for the Laws,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hat it is five to one you lose the Cause.</l>
               <l>In troth, my Lord, the Case is very sad,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ough to make a wiser Man stark mad.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t I'll advise your Lordship what to do,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>is plain, that they their Madness will pursue.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hey hope to see you soon advanc'd on high,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ost sweetly dangling 'twixt the Earth and Sky;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e reaking Balsom from your Breeches dropping,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>d greedy Handkerchiefs the Relick sopping;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hilst on their Heads a Chrystal shower descends,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nd all their Shoulders o'er it self extends.</l>
               <l>This 'tis they mean, 'tis this they wou'd have done,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t I wou'd chouse 'em e'ery Mothers Son,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>roth I'd e'en hang my self, 'tis quickly done.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> you've no Halter, never make a pother,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ke but a Garter, one's as good as tother:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>r Lord! should such a Man as you submit</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o be the publick laughter of each grinning Cit!</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>se my Lord take a Razor, never fear,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nd cut your Lordships Throat from Ear to Ear.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>is feasible enough, you know who did it,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nd you are valiant, Sir, what need you dread it?</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t both the Jug'lar Veins tho' if you can,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>se they'll say <hi>Essex</hi> was the stouter Man,</l>
            </lg>
            <closer>
               <signed>I am your Lordships, in any thing of this Nature</signed>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>
                  <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>rom the little House over a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst</hi> Tyburn, <hi>where the people are almost dead with expectation of you.</hi>
               </p>
            </postscript>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>
               <hi>Dangerfield</hi>'s Ghost to <hi>Jeffreys.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>REvenge! Revenge!</hi> my injur'd <hi>Shade</hi> begins</l>
               <l>To haunt thy guilty Soul, and scourge thy sins:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or since to me thou ow'st the heaviest score,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hose <hi>living</hi> words tormented thee before,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hen <hi>Dead,</hi> I'm come to plague thee yet once more.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>on't start away, nor think thy <hi>Brass</hi> to hide,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ut see the dismal <hi>shape</hi> in which I dy'd!</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>y Body all deform'd with putrid Gore,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>eeding my <hi>Soul</hi> away at every <hi>Pore;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>sht faster on by <hi>Francis,</hi> less unkind;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>y <hi>Body</hi> swoln, and bloated as thy <hi>Mind.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>his dangling <hi>Eye-ball</hi> rolls about in vain,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> ever to find its proper <hi>seat</hi> again,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he hollow <hi>Cell</hi> usurpt by Blood and <hi>Brain:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he trembling <hi>Jury</hi>'s Verdict ought to be</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>rder'd at once, by</hi> Francis, <hi>and by Thee.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The <hi>Groans</hi> of Orphans, and the pondrous <hi>guilt</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>f all the Blood that thou hast ever spilt;</l>
               <l>Thy Countreys <hi>Curse,</hi> the Rabbles <hi>spite,</hi> and all</l>
               <l>Those <hi>Wishes</hi> sent thee since thy <hi>long-wisht</hi> Fall;</l>
               <l>The <hi>Nobles</hi> just Revenge, so bravely bought,</l>
               <l>For all the Ills thy <hi>Insolence</hi> has wrought:</l>
               <l>May these and more their utmost force combine,</l>
               <l>Joyn all their <hi>wrongs,</hi> and mix their <hi>Cries</hi> with mine.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And see, if <hi>Terror</hi> has not struck thee blind;</l>
               <l>See here a long, a ghastly <hi>Train</hi> behind!</l>
               <l>Far, far, from utmost <hi>WEST</hi> they crowd away,</l>
               <l>And hov'ring o're, fright back the <hi>sickly</hi> Day;</l>
               <l>Had the poor Wretches <hi>sinn'd</hi> as much as <hi>Thee,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Thou shou'dst not have forgot <hi>Humanity:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Who e'er in <hi>Blood</hi> can so much pleasure take?</l>
               <l>Tho' an ill <hi>Judge</hi> wou'd a good <hi>Hang-man</hi> make.</l>
               <l>Each hollows in thy Ears, — <hi>Prepare! Prepare</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For what thou <hi>must,</hi> yet what thou <hi>canst</hi> not bear!</l>
               <l>Each, at thy <hi>Heart</hi> a bloody <hi>Dagger</hi> aims,</l>
               <l>Upward to <hi>Gibbets</hi> point, downward to endless <hi>Flames.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>A Congratulatory Poem to His Royal Highness the Prince of <hi>ORANGE.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>VVElcome (Great Sir) unto a Drooping Isle,</l>
               <l>Whose Peace a slavish Thraldom did beguile;</l>
               <l>Whose Native and just Properties infring'd,</l>
               <l>Whose Fundamental Laws are quite unhing'd;</l>
               <l>Whose Rights in an unequal ballance weigh'd,</l>
               <l>Whose fainting Church calls your assisting aid;</l>
               <l>Welcome thou grand supporter of her Cause;</l>
               <l>Welcome thou great Restorer of our Laws.</l>
               <l>Wise Heaven thought fit that you alone should be</l>
               <l>The Antidote against our Misery:</l>
               <l>That all our Wishes should in you be Crown'd,</l>
               <l>That you alone should heal our bleeding Wound.</l>
               <l>You are the Rock on whom we do rely,</l>
               <l>With you we'll swim, or sink, we'll live, or die:</l>
               <l>You gently rule us with your awful Nod,</l>
               <l>You are our Standard, and almost our God.</l>
               <l>Both Church, and the declining State invite</l>
               <l>You the vast Center of their chief Delight;</l>
               <l>They beg that you their Darkness would expel,</l>
               <l>And make a Heaven of their present Hell.</l>
               <l>'Tis done! Chear up, the Rising Sun appears,</l>
               <l>His splendent Rays suck up our falling Tears;</l>
               <l>We'll hate the meager looks of Sorrow now,</l>
               <l>With Laurel Wreaths true Joy shall crown each Brow.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Christ dy'd a bitter Death upon the Cross</l>
               <l>That we might live, he wholly did Ingross</l>
               <l>All our Paternal sins, he bore them all,</l>
               <l>Which we Contracted have by <hi>Adam</hi>'s Fall:</l>
               <l>He vanquishi Sin, and Satan overcame,</l>
               <l>And set Mankind on even ground again.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb n="24" facs="tcp:98643:12"/>
               <l>So you, Great Prince! our boasting Foes subdue,</l>
               <l>And curb the Pride of all the Popish Crew;</l>
               <l>With hazard of your Life our Chain you've broke,</l>
               <l>And bravely freed us from the hated Yoke:</l>
               <l>With vast Expence you have our Freedom bought,</l>
               <l>And the Church out of the House of Bondage brought.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Hence Jesuits, ye Instruments of Hell,</l>
               <l>That fill with easie Souls the Devil's Cell:</l>
               <l>To cheat and gull the Ignorant's your Trade,</l>
               <l>Ye're subtle Devils all in Masquerade:</l>
               <l>Wretches, be gone to some more willing Land,</l>
               <l>Tis Sacred, Hallowed ground whereon ye stand;</l>
               <l>And shall not basely be prophaned twice</l>
               <l>By such a knotted trumpery of Vice.</l>
               <l>Hence Popery, thou bain of all our Bliss,</l>
               <l>Thou treach'rous Poys'ner of our Happiness:</l>
               <l>Unfetter'd now, and loosed from our Pain,</l>
               <l>We'll never reassume thy galling Chain,</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Now <hi>Peters</hi> die a Martyr for thy Church,</l>
               <l>And leave not Holy Mother in the lurch:</l>
               <l>Grac'd with fine Hemp at the Gallows take a swing,</l>
               <l>And swiftly fly to Heaven in a string.</l>
               <l>But first Absolve your poor deluded King.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>What Change is this? under a strange disguise,</l>
               <l>The great Lord <hi>Wem</hi>'s become <hi>George Jeffereys;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>His Fate is this, He'll dreaded <hi>Tyburn</hi> view,</l>
               <l>And so bid Arbitrary Law adiew,</l>
               <l>And make his long expected Dream prove true.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then <hi>Herbert, Wright,</hi> and <hi>Jenner</hi> steer their Course</l>
               <l>The same broad way as you (poor <hi>George</hi>) did yours:</l>
               <l>Then come the rest of the Fraternity,</l>
               <l>Sworn faithful Brothers in Iniquity;</l>
               <l>For when their Captain has his life resign'd,</l>
               <l>They, Noble Souls, will scorn to lag behind.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Repent ye base Betrayers of your Trust,</l>
               <l>Unto your knowing Consciences unjust:</l>
               <l>False to your Country, to your King untrue,</l>
               <l>Religion's but an empty Name with you.</l>
               <l>Hang now like Dogs, 'tis meet you should inherit</l>
               <l>The due, and full proportion of your Merit.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Justice is done! I hear brave <hi>Orange</hi> come,</l>
               <l>And with Concern pronounce your fatal Doom.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>England</hi> rejoyce, for now your only Care,</l>
               <l>Is but the burthen of your Bliss to bear:</l>
               <l>Strip every Laurel, every Myrtle bow,</l>
               <l>For Wreaths to adorn and load his Sacred Brow;</l>
               <l>Eccho with chearful shouts his glorious Name,</l>
               <l>The amazing Wonder, and discourse of Fame:</l>
               <l>Ring Bells, a Waxen Pope in fire destroy,</l>
               <l>And shew all outward acts of inward joy.</l>
               <l>The Lambs do play, the Birds by instinct sing,</l>
               <l>As if it were at the approaching Spring;</l>
               <l>And every Creature makes a Melody;</l>
               <l>Do all things else rejoyce, and shall not I?</l>
               <l>I'll be the first, and will in mighty Verse</l>
               <l>Your Noble Deeds and Glorious Acts rehearse.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>A Congratulatory Poem to Hi<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Royal Higness the Prince o<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <hi>Orange,</hi> or his Welcome to th<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> City of <hi>London. Veni, Vidi, Vici.</hi>
            </head>
            <l>HAil mighty Prince! this Poem on you waits,</l>
            <l>As the first Offering that Celebrates</l>
            <l>Your welcome to the Town, almost Destroy'd</l>
            <l>By Priest-craft, and by you again Reviv'd;</l>
            <l>This Glorious Day (in which all Triumphs Live)</l>
            <l>To Heaven, and you, Great Sir, we only give.</l>
            <l>When <hi>Jove</hi> first made the World, he ask'd no more</l>
            <l>Of us, but taught us whom we should implore</l>
            <l>As then, so now 'tis our peculiar care,</l>
            <l>With Joyful thanks to gratifie your ear,</l>
            <l>Who from the Dust has rais'd our Grov'ling State,</l>
            <l>Which hung upon the weakest Wheel of Fate</l>
            <l>An Act so high and past Mankinds believing</l>
            <l>That none but you could e'er think of retrieving</l>
            <l>Yet more, they who this Nation would inthral,</l>
            <l>Do fill your Triumph with their wretched Fall,</l>
            <l>But what does Heaven impart when they design</l>
            <l>To Act something that's Noble and Divine?</l>
            <l>Prophetick Stars this happy time ne'er knew,</l>
            <l>This Secret only Lodg'd in Heaven, and you,</l>
            <l>And mighty Prince, (since Fate decrees it so)</l>
            <l>Our Lives unto your Generous Sword we owe,</l>
            <l>Not only, but Estates and Liberty,</l>
            <l>Which is the sum of all felicity.</l>
            <l>Exhal'd from sullen frowns our Kingdom's blest,</l>
            <l>And in the umbrage of your Laurels rest,</l>
            <l>Whilst Joy like Lightning in Tempestuous Storms</l>
            <l>Dazles the World, and fills it with Alarms,</l>
            <l>Joy now to Loudest Triumph makes its way,</l>
            <l>And we no difference know 'tween Night and Day,</l>
            <l>Our Souls transported in strong Raptures move,</l>
            <l>And yet United are in artless Love,</l>
            <l>Joy now and Love so very well agree,</l>
            <l>As if this year was the first <hi>Jubilee,</hi>
            </l>
            <l>Of Care and Business we'll no more allow</l>
            <l>Since Deathless Laurels flourish on your brow,</l>
            <l>Go on brave Prince what i'st you can't effect</l>
            <l>Whom Heaven with prosperous Stars does still protect,</l>
            <l>The fury of your Sword, let the <hi>French</hi> feel,</l>
            <l>That Kingdom is design'd by you to recl;</l>
            <l>Pull down their Gaudy Pride which long hath stood,</l>
            <l>And their own Fields Manure with their own Blood,</l>
            <l>Come here's the Prince's Health, a Brimmer round,</l>
            <l>And all the <hi>Popish</hi> Interest Confound.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb n="25" facs="tcp:98643:12"/>
            <head>To make a Catholick Pudding.</head>
            <l>OF <hi>Oates</hi> new thrasht at <hi>Tyburn</hi> take Two pound,</l>
            <l>Of <hi>Chios Wine</hi> enough the same to dround;</l>
            <l>Of <hi>Malmsbury</hi> and <hi>Hobbs</hi> take Ounces eight,</l>
            <l>Of a Quacks Conscience add an equal Weight:</l>
            <l>Of <hi>Jury's</hi> finely pack'd take once Ounce more,</l>
            <l>Six <hi>Irish</hi> Witnesses just come ashore;</l>
            <l>Season it all with <hi>Atheistick</hi> Lies,</l>
            <l>'Twill make a Pudding that shall clear your Eyes.</l>
            <l>Here <hi>Antichrist</hi> may freely treat his own Guests,</l>
            <l>For the Receit is Learned Dr. <hi>C—sts.</hi>
            </l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>UPON THE Execrable Murther Of the Right Honourable <hi>ARTHƲR</hi> Earl of <hi>Essex.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>MOrtality wou'd be too frail to hear,</l>
               <l>How <hi>ESSEX</hi> fell, and not dissolve with fear;</l>
               <l>Did not more generous Rage take off the Blow,</l>
               <l>And by his Blood the steps to Vengeance show.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Tow'r was for the Tragedy design'd,</l>
               <l>And to be slaughter'd he is first confin'd:</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>s fetter'd <hi>Victims</hi> to the Altar go.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ut why must Noble <hi>ESSEX</hi> perish so?</l>
               <l>Why with such Fury drag'd into his Tomb,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>urther'd by Slaves, and sacrific'd to <hi>Rome?</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>By Stealth they kill, and with a secret Stroke</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ence that Voice, which charm'd when e're it spoke.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he bleeding Orifice o're-flow'd the Ground,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ore like some mighty D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>luge than a Wound.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hrough the large space his Blood and Vitals glide,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>d his whole Body might have past beside.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he reeking Crimson swell'd into a Flood,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nd stream'd a second time in <hi>Capel</hi>'s Blood.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e's in his Son again to Death pursu'd,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>n Instance of the high'st Ingratitude.</l>
               <l>They then malitious Stratagems imploy,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ith Life, his dear Honour to destroy;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>nd make his Fame extinguish with his Breath,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>n Act beyond the Cruelties of Death.</l>
               <l>Here Murther is in all its Shapes complete,</l>
               <l>As <hi>Lines,</hi> united in their <hi>Centre</hi> meet;</l>
               <l>Form'd by the blackest <hi>Politicks</hi> of Hell;</l>
               <l>Was <hi>Cain</hi> so div'lish when his Brother fell?</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>He that contrives, or his own Fate desires,</l>
               <l>Wants Courage, and for fear of Death expires;</l>
               <l>But mighty <hi>ESSEX</hi> was in all things brave,</l>
               <l>Neither to <hi>Hope,</hi> nor to <hi>Despair,</hi> a Slave.</l>
               <l>He had a Soul too <hi>Innocent,</hi> and <hi>Great,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To fear, or to anticipate his Fate:</l>
               <l>Yet their exalted Impudence and Guilt,</l>
               <l>Charge on himself the precious Blood they spilt.</l>
               <l>So were the <hi>Protestants</hi> some years ago,</l>
               <l>Destroy'd in <hi>Ireland</hi> without a Foe.</l>
               <l>By their own barbarous Hands the Mad-men die,</l>
               <l>And Massacre themselves, they know not why:</l>
               <l>Whilst the kind <hi>Irish</hi> howl to see the Go<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e,</l>
               <l>And Pious <hi>Catholicks</hi> their Fate deplore.</l>
               <l>If you refuse to trust erroneous Fame,</l>
               <l>Royal <hi>Mac-Ninny</hi> will confirm the same.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>We have lost more in injur'd <hi>Capel</hi>'s <hi>Heir,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Than the poor Bankrupt Age can e're repair.</l>
               <l>Nature indulg'd him so, that there we saw</l>
               <l>All the choice Strokes her steady Hand cou'd draw.</l>
               <l>He the Old <hi>English</hi> Glory did revive.</l>
               <l>In him we had <hi>Plantagenets</hi> alive.</l>
               <l>Grandeur and Fortune, and a vast Renown,</l>
               <l>Fit to support the Lustre of a Crown.</l>
               <l>All these in him were potently conjoin'd,</l>
               <l>But all was too <hi>ignoble</hi> for his Mind:</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Wisdom</hi> and <hi>Vertue,</hi> properties Divine,</l>
               <l>Those, Godlike-<hi>ESSEX,</hi> were entirely thine.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>In this Great Name he's still preserv'd alive,</l>
               <l>And will to all succeeding Times survive.</l>
               <l>With just Progression, as the constant Sun</l>
               <l>Doth move, and through its bright <hi>Ecliptick</hi> Run.</l>
               <l>For whilst his Dust do's undistinguish'd lye,</l>
               <l>And his blest Soul is soar'd above the Sky,</l>
               <l>Fame shall below his parted Breath supply.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>A true and full Account of a late Confe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence between the wonderful <hi>Speaking Head</hi> and Father <hi>Pulton,</hi> as it was related by the <hi>Heads</hi> own Mouth to Dr. <hi>F—r, 1686.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>I That was once an humble Logg,</l>
               <l>The pissing Post for every Rogue;</l>
               <pb n="26" facs="tcp:98643:13"/>
               <l>And did hope for nothing higher,</l>
               <l>Than to grace a <hi>Christmass</hi> Fire,</l>
               <l>From th' Element escaped hard,</l>
               <l>By th' Favour of <hi>F—et</hi> Shepherd;</l>
               <l>Who, being a Friend to <hi>Mathematicks,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Do's for <hi>Virtuos<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi>'s lay Tricks;</l>
               <l>Did procure a Man of Art,</l>
               <l>That gave me Voice Articulate,</l>
               <l>Taught me Tongues the most difficile,</l>
               <l>To sing <hi>Sawney,</hi> Laugh and Whistle.</l>
               <l>Follow'd now by Court and City,</l>
               <l>I confound with my strange Di<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ty,</l>
               <l>Both the Learned and the Witty:</l>
               <l>And make all the Talk at <hi>Betty</hi>'<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>,</l>
               <l>By the help of my Friend <hi>P—s.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For you Wits were always good</l>
               <l>To the Family of Wood,</l>
               <l>And before kept such a puther</l>
               <l>With the Groaning Board my Brother,</l>
               <l>Some Men think you know our Mother.</l>
               <l>And I hope both you and they Sir,</l>
               <l>Will favour me sweet Dr. <hi>F—r,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To help me out but with one Jest;</l>
               <l>Let me alone for all the rest;</l>
               <l>For my wondrous Voices sound,</l>
               <l>Is much admir'd by the <hi>Beau-Mond,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Who to me pay more Devotion</l>
               <l>Than to pretty <hi>Punches</hi> Motion.</l>
               <l>Many a Lady bright and fine</l>
               <l>Lays her Cherry Lips to mine,</l>
               <l>And without offence I smack her</l>
               <l>Till I rub off all my Lacker;</l>
               <l>With that Sex I more prevail</l>
               <l>Than any Head that wants a Tail.</l>
               <l>The King to Court sent for my Timber</l>
               <l>As kind as if I had been a Member,</l>
               <l>And found me an obedient Head</l>
               <l>That did agree to all he said;</l>
               <l>Which being strange, pleas'd him so much,</l>
               <l>He wish'd that all the House were such;</l>
               <l>And 'twould much advance his Cause,</l>
               <l>If such Noddles could make Laws.</l>
               <l>This indeed 's a mighty Comfort,</l>
               <l>But, alas! I am paid home for't.</l>
               <l>Buisy Priests with their Disputing,</l>
               <l>Reasoning, Arguing, and Confuting,</l>
               <l>Who with Charms Ecclesiastick,</l>
               <l>Can make good <hi>Catholick</hi> of a Stick:</l>
               <l>Do torment and plague me, more</l>
               <l>Than without Ears I ever bore;</l>
               <l>May I be a Logg again,</l>
               <l>To avoid their Noisy Train.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Pulton</hi> t' other Night did come,</l>
               <l>(If I Lie, may I be Dumb,</l>
               <l>Or may a Plague I wish my Foes,</l>
               <l>Will <hi>R—s</hi> blow into my Nose,)</l>
               <l>And brought a Letter sign'd S. <hi>Petre,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That he'd privately Confer with me.</l>
               <l>I at the Challenge did not flinch,</l>
               <l>But bid him sit down on my Bench;</l>
               <l>And since he had so good a Warrant,</l>
               <l>Blow in my Mouth, and tell his Errand.</l>
               <l>Says he, I Missionary come,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Ad Partes Infidelit<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For your Faith cannot be good,</l>
               <l>That springs from Shepherds and hard Wood:</l>
               <l>I to all Blockheads am the Legate,</l>
               <l>And gain some in spight of <hi>Gl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>gat.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>They alone our Business must do,</l>
               <l>Who han't a grain of Sense to trust to.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>'Tis not my Province to Confute</l>
               <l>Those that think and can Dispute;</l>
               <l>And here we need not such Expences,</l>
               <l>Since our Notion suits our Senses.</l>
               <l>Nothing is so apt and fit</l>
               <l>For our Doctrin, as your Wit,</l>
               <l>And he is most our Enemy.</l>
               <l>Who is most removed from thee.</l>
               <l>Oh! happy Off-spring of the <hi>M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ple,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To praise thee enough I am not able.</l>
               <l>Oh! what comfort dost thou show Men</l>
               <l>In thy lucky Faces <hi>Omen?</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Times will come again, I see,</l>
               <l>When <hi>England</hi> shall adore a Tree;</l>
               <l>When Oracles old Poets shall utter,</l>
               <l>Wafers bleed, and Flints sweat Butter.</l>
               <l>If in Mother Church you stood,</l>
               <l>You'd do Wonders like the Rood;</l>
               <l>In her Sacred Bosom foster'd,</l>
               <l>What might we hope from such a Costard;</l>
               <l>For you might convert the Nation,</l>
               <l>Since you speak by Inspiration.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>While he thus foam'd with Holy Rage,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>B—y</hi> with pale Visage,</l>
               <l>To bring my late Conveyance home,</l>
               <l>Came by chance into the Room,</l>
               <l>And look'd on him as well as me,</l>
               <l>Like Ghost of little <hi>Shaftsbury;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The frighted Priest let fall the Matter,</l>
               <l>And headlong down the Stairs did clatter;</l>
               <l>Nor could sustain in any place</l>
               <l>The Terror of that hated Face.</l>
               <l>I in this Deliverance blest,</l>
               <l>Got in my Chest, and went to rest.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>An <hi>Irish</hi> Prophecy.</head>
            <l>THere was a Prophecy lately found in a <hi>Bogg,</hi>
            </l>
            <l>That <hi>Ireland</hi> should be ruin'd by an Ass and a Dog</l>
            <l>This Prophecy's true, and now come to pass,</l>
            <l>For <hi>T—ts</hi> a Dog, and <hi>T—l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> an Ass.</l>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb n="27" facs="tcp:98643:13"/>
            <head>The DEPONENTS.</head>
            <lg>
               <l>THE mighty Monarch of this <hi>British</hi> Isle,</l>
               <l>Disturb'd to hear his Subjects prate and smile,</l>
               <l>That he is so content to own a Son,</l>
               <l>For to inherit th' Imperial Throne,</l>
               <l>To please his Q—n, and put by both his own.</l>
               <l>But finding <hi>England</hi> not so Credulous,</l>
               <l>And Clear-ey'd <hi>O—ge</hi> more suspect than us,</l>
               <l>By Instigation of the <hi>Q.</hi> and <hi>P.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>He Summons all together as you see,</l>
               <l>And there declares his own Sufficiency.</l>
               <l>He says his Subjects Minds so poyson'd are,</l>
               <l>They'l not believe God bless'd him with an Heir;</l>
               <l>But to convince them they are in the wrong,</l>
               <l>In comes the Swearers, and Depose as long</l>
               <l>A Narrative as perjur'd <hi>O—es</hi> could do;</l>
               <l>What these Depose unquestionably's true,</l>
               <l>Our King says so, who dare say other now?</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>There's Lords, Knights, Ladies, Squires, Quacks and all</l>
               <l>The Papal Locust that infect <hi>White-Hall;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>They Swear what King would have, to gain their Ends,</l>
               <l>Since he's a Prince that ne're forgets his Friends.</l>
               <l>But Witness Bishops, for your Loyalty</l>
               <l>He makes you great, he did bestow on ye,</l>
               <l>To keep you safe, his strongest Fort:</l>
               <l>While ye were there, the Tower was the Court.</l>
               <l>All fled from <hi>James</hi> to you for Blessing came;</l>
               <l>Imprisonment Immortaliz'd your Name;</l>
               <l>Bishops of <hi>Englands</hi> Church are Men of Fame.</l>
               <l>And since his dire Designs in Law have fail'd,</l>
               <l>He seems to smile; You are to Council call'd.</l>
               <l>To hear the Worthy Loyal Swearers swear,</l>
               <l>That at the Birth of <hi>Wales</hi>'s Prince they were.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And first begins Old <hi>England</hi>'s Barren Q.</l>
               <l>That at her Sisters Labour was not seen,</l>
               <l>Till all was past; yet for the Holy Cause,</l>
               <l>She'll do what e're she can to blind the Laws</l>
               <l>Of <hi>England,</hi> and doth there declare, and say,</l>
               <l>She hastned to the Q. that very Day,</l>
               <l>And never stirr'd till this great Prince was born,</l>
               <l>For th' Nations Glory, but he proves their Scorn;</l>
               <l>Except of these that on him daily wait,</l>
               <l>Whose Loyal Love is only to be great.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Next comes Old <hi>P—is,</hi> who a Story feigns,</l>
               <l>Of Riff Raff stuff, to fill the Peoples Brains,</l>
               <l>Of what she saw, and knew about the thing;</l>
               <l>And in a modest Circumstance doth bring</l>
               <l>Of something, which into the World he brought,</l>
               <l>And by the Doctors gave him, as she thought.</l>
               <l>Now as a Governess she tends his Grace,</l>
               <l>And would not for all Heaven quit her place;</l>
               <l>So sweet a Babe, so fine a hopeful Lad.</l>
               <l>The forward'st Son the Father ever had.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then <hi>A—ns</hi> Countess with her Oath comes in</l>
               <l>That at the Princes Birth her self had been,</l>
               <l>And how she heard Complainings from the Q.</l>
               <l>Of little Pains, and then the Child was seen;</l>
               <l>But Oh! He did not cry; the Q. baul'd out</l>
               <l>For fear 'twas Dead, but Granny clear'd the Doubt.</l>
               <l>And further Honour this great Lady had;</l>
               <l>She saw Smock spoil'd with Milk, (the Sign was bad)</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And <hi>P—gh</hi> could not be beguil'd,</l>
               <l>Knowing the Fathers Strength, (at thought she smil'd)</l>
               <l>She saw Queens Smock, and swears she was with Child.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>While Pious <hi>S—nd</hi> to Chappel went,</l>
               <l>On purpose to receive the Sacrament;</l>
               <l>Devotion was so great, she disobey'd</l>
               <l>Her Majesty, and said, When she had Pray'd</l>
               <l>She'd wait on Her; But hearing that the Prince</l>
               <l>Was hastning to the World, this, this pretence</l>
               <l>Soon brought our Saint-like Lady quick from thence;</l>
               <l>And from her bended Knees flew to the Q—n,</l>
               <l>And there saw all the sight was to be seen.</l>
               <l>The Bed was warm'd, and into it she went,</l>
               <l>And ask'd the K. if for the Guests he'd sent,</l>
               <l>And lingring Pain she had, and seem'd to fear</l>
               <l>'Twould not be Born, till all the Fools were there;</l>
               <l>But by her Midwife was assur'd, one Pain</l>
               <l>Would bring the Prince into the World amain.</l>
               <l>But Faithless Q—n! The Child did lye so high,</l>
               <l>She'd not believe but <hi>Judith</hi> told a Lie;</l>
               <l>And such an Honour to this Deponent granted,</l>
               <l>'Tis hardly more by th' Pope for to be Sainted.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>R—mon</hi> Swears she stood by <hi>S—land,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Near the Q—ns Bed, just by the Midwifes Hand,</l>
               <l>And saw his Highness taken out of Bed,</l>
               <l>Fit for a Crown to Adorn his Princely Head.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>F—gall</hi> Depos'd, that in the Q—ns distress,</l>
               <l>She stood at the Beds-Feet, just by <hi>M—ss,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And saw the Prince into the World did come,</l>
               <l>And by <hi>D—dy</hi> carried from the Room.</l>
               <l>Then Painted <hi>B—ley</hi> early in the Morn,</l>
               <l>Came to St. <hi>James</hi>'s to see his Highness born;</l>
               <l>With all the hast she could she up did rise,</l>
               <l>Soon Dress'd, she came by Nine a Clock precise,</l>
               <l>And found Her Majesty was in the Bed,</l>
               <l>And groaning dismally, she further said,</l>
               <l>Cry'd to the Midwife, <hi>Do not the Child part?</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Old Granny crav'd her leave; With all her Heart,</l>
               <l>She granted what the Beldam did desire,</l>
               <l>And certain 'tis there was no danger nigh her:</l>
               <l>Crying, Oh King! where are you fled?</l>
               <l>He said, I'm kneeling Madam, on your Bed.</l>
               <l>This plain Deponent bellows Bawdy forth,</l>
               <l>To be expos'd both <hi>East, West, South</hi> and <hi>North,</hi>
               </l>
               <pb n="28" facs="tcp:98643:14"/>
               <l>Without e're fear or shame; bars Modesty,</l>
               <l>For to out-face the World with such a Lie.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then Pocky <hi>B—sis</hi> the next comes in,</l>
               <l>And says, She saw the Cast of <hi>Charles</hi>'s Queen,</l>
               <l>And hearing that the Queen in Labour was,</l>
               <l>She hurr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ed in without a Call or Pass.</l>
               <l>VVith this Excuse (she knew she was forgot)</l>
               <l>VVhere she talks Bawdy, she Impudents, what not?</l>
               <l>Expose her self in Print to shew her Love;</l>
               <l>Exalted by the King, and one above;</l>
               <l>She'll Lie and Swear, Forswear, to prop the Cause,</l>
               <l>That baffles <hi>Englands</hi> sound and wholsom Laws.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then Lady <hi>W—grave,</hi> who was there before</l>
               <l>This Royal Babe was launched from the Shore,</l>
               <l>And heard her Majesty cry out full sore.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then <hi>C—ne</hi> and sottish <hi>Went—th</hi> say the same,</l>
               <l>VVith <hi>S—yer, Wald-ve; D—son,</hi> that they came</l>
               <l>And saw this VVonder which the VVorld won't own,</l>
               <l>And blames their little Faith; to think this Son</l>
               <l>Is <hi>Spurious,</hi> and not in truth proceeding</l>
               <l>From Majesty, when they all saw him Bleeding;</l>
               <l>Nay, gave him of his Blood (squeez'd from the String)</l>
               <l>That did the Royal Babe into the VVorld bring.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then <hi>Br—ley, T—ni,</hi> and <hi>Nan C—ry</hi> too,</l>
               <l>Swear they saw all the VVork that was to do,</l>
               <l>And more by half is sworn than they'l prove true.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then comes <hi>De—dy</hi> the great Nurse,</l>
               <l>VVho with the Q—n is all in all in trust;</l>
               <l>And swears that <hi>Dan—rs,</hi> Maid to Princess <hi>Ann,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>VVas joy'd to see this little Royal Man,</l>
               <l>VVith former mark on Eye, which us'd to be</l>
               <l>On all Q. <hi>Mary</hi>'s Royal Progeny;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>J—es</hi> seem'd to doubt that which before he knew,</l>
               <l>And fear'd this Treacherous Nurse not told him true;</l>
               <l>But he must peep and see the Royal <hi>Elf,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And joy'd as if he'd got him his own self.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>For Mrs. <hi>W—ks,</hi> who doubts but she would say,</l>
               <l>She brought the <hi>Prince</hi> that very day;</l>
               <l>And told the <hi>K—g,</hi> the trembling <hi>Q—n</hi> did fear</l>
               <l>'Twould be hard Labour (tho no Child was there;)</l>
               <l>Explains most impudently those Concerns,</l>
               <l>That follow VVomen when they cast their Barns;</l>
               <l>And what cares she, the Hereticks she'l blind,</l>
               <l>And then we fear the <hi>K—g</hi> will prove most kind;</l>
               <l>To all those VVretches which swear to his mind.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then comes the VVasher-woman Mrs. <hi>P—ce,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>VVho says, that to the <hi>Q—n</hi> she's Laundress;</l>
               <l>And there declares a Story of hot Linnen,</l>
               <l>That us'd to come just from Child-bearing VVomen.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Rich—nd</hi> and <hi>Li—d,</hi> and brave <hi>Ma—all,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Tho not at Labour they believe it all;</l>
               <l>And fain would be believ'd, if these Tools</l>
               <l>By swearing falsly, could make us such Fools;</l>
               <l>They give such Demonstrations, that do lye</l>
               <l>As much aside as they do Modesty.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then comes great <hi>G—ge</hi> of <hi>England, Ch—lour,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>VVho was, with Expedition call'd to th' Labour;</l>
               <l>The <hi>Q—n</hi> cry'd out as VVomen us'd to do,</l>
               <l>And he believes the <hi>P—ce</hi> is real too,</l>
               <l>But not so certain, nor 'tis fear'd so true</l>
               <l>As he wears Horns, that were by <hi>M—fort</hi> made,</l>
               <l>Them and his Noise makes all the Fools afraid;</l>
               <l>Tongue runs at random, and Horns pushes those</l>
               <l>That are so learn'd his Lordship to Oppose;</l>
               <l>He fears to act no wretched Villanies,</l>
               <l>He dreads no Torments for inventing Lies,</l>
               <l>For he of Heav'n is sure when e're he dies.</l>
               <l>Thanks to the care of fond Indulgent VVife,</l>
               <l>To make Atonement for his wicked Life;</l>
               <l>Damns her own Soul, VVhores with all she cou'd,</l>
               <l>To allay the impetious Salleys of her Blood.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Lord <hi>P—dent</hi> comes next, that's now cashier'd,</l>
               <l>For only speaking of the Truth 'tis fear'd;</l>
               <l>Yet he for to be great again at Court,</l>
               <l>Would be forsworn tho he is damned for't.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then <hi>A—del</hi> of <hi>W—dour</hi> Privy Seal,</l>
               <l>Was so concern'd that he Her Pains did feel;</l>
               <l>And 'tis believ'd this tender hearted Man,</l>
               <l>Did feel as much as Majesty did then;</l>
               <l>He shew'd indeed concern'd to mighty <hi>W—m,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Who knew too much to have concern for him;</l>
               <l>But satisfi'd the Fool it would be past,</l>
               <l>And wonder'd much her Pain so long did last.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then in comes my Lord <hi>All Pride</hi> with Modesty,</l>
               <l>And seems unwilling, to affirm a Lie;</l>
               <l>With stately Gesture he did himself excuse,</l>
               <l>But setting Hand to Paper can't refuse.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then foolish <hi>C—n</hi> comes and doth depose,</l>
               <l>A mark he hath that he the Prince well knows;</l>
               <l>If't be his Lordships Mark he ne're must rule.</l>
               <l>For <hi>Europe</hi> knows that he's mark'd for a Fool.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then comes <hi>F—sham,</hi> that haughty <hi>Beàu,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And tells a Tale of <hi>den</hi> and <hi>dat</hi> and <hi>how;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Tho he's no more believ'd than all the rest,</l>
               <l>Only poor Man, he fain would do his best,</l>
               <l>And be rewarded as when come from <hi>West.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Earl of <hi>M—ray,</hi> that <hi>Alexander</hi> Great,</l>
               <l>Believes it was the <hi>K—g</hi> that did the Feat;</l>
               <l>And that this Son is true and not a Cheat.</l>
               <l>Then <hi>M—ton</hi> and <hi>M—ford</hi> both explain'd</l>
               <l>The Business which they from the <hi>K—g</hi> had gain'd;</l>
               <l>As knowing Men his Majesty did trust,</l>
               <l>His Consorts Secrets, hoping they'd be just;</l>
               <l>To his endeared Son our mighty <hi>Prince,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That as he thought would hide his Impotence;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>G—n</hi> too, with confidence pretends,</l>
               <l>It is true born, but 'tis for his own Ends.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And <hi>F—x</hi> a Story tells of God knows what,</l>
               <l>To fool the Nation's, all he would be at;</l>
               <l>He keeps in Favour with his Princely Grace,</l>
               <l>He Fawns and Flatters for to keep his Place.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb n="29" facs="tcp:98643:14"/>
               <l>Then famous <hi>Sea—urgh</hi> and <hi>Wi—ly,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ith <hi>W—ve, B—dy,</hi> and <hi>A—nd</hi> do lye;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>d bring their Circumstances to convince</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> be World that 'tis a real High Born Prince;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hus they stick out at nothing that will do</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he Nation wrong, and bring to <hi>England</hi> woe.</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>se Mercenary Slaves! for a Kings Smile</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ould <hi>Spurious</hi> Issue rear, and us beguile;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>at fawn on him, and more observe a nod,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>han fear the Vengeance of an angry God;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>d on the turn o'th' times would all fly back,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>od let his Highness Interest go to wrack.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Two Depositions more to Council sent,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ham'd to appear to farther the intent</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <hi>Popish</hi> Principles, and Perjuries;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e but the Devil could invent such Lyes.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Then after this the King himself declares</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> don't design with <hi>England</hi> to make Wars;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t he such Aggravations hath of late,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>at he must needs be angry with the State;</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Specious Prologue, he concludes with all;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t ah, the Protestants he vows shall fall▪</l>
               <l>Sacrifice to <hi>Rome,</hi> and His Revenge;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>en Souldiers fear not Fools, but scorn to Cringe;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> resolute and stout, and scorn to sell</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ur Souls to <hi>Rome,</hi> but send the <hi>Pope</hi> to <hi>Hell.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>Father <hi>PETRE</hi>'s Policy DISCOVERED: OR, THE Prince of <hi>WALES</hi> Prov'd a <hi>Popish Perkin.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>N <hi>Rome</hi> there is a most fearful Rout;</l>
               <l>And what do you think it is about?</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>cause the Birth of the Babe's come out.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing Lulla by Babee, by, by, by.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e Jesuits swear the Midwife told Tales,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>d Ruin'd his Highness the Prince of <hi>Wales;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e's a Jade for her Pains, <hi>Gutsplutter-anails.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing Lulla, &amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>he Popish Crew did all protest,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hat Twenty Great Men would swear at least,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hey see his <hi>Welch</hi> Highness creep out of His Nest.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing Lulla, &amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Goggle-Ey'd Monster in the <hi>Tower,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>He peep'd at his Birth for above an Hour,</l>
               <l>And 'twas a true Prince of <hi>Wales</hi> he Swore.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing Lulla, &amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Another great Lord, both Grave and Wise,</l>
               <l>Stood peeping between Her Majesties Thighs;</l>
               <l>He look'd through a Glass for to save his Eyes.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing Lulla, &amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Both were so well satisfy'd,</l>
               <l>They knew sweet Babe from a Thousand they cry'd;</l>
               <l>'Twas Born with the Print of a Tile on his side.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing Lulla, &amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Some say 'tis a Prince of <hi>Wales</hi> by Right,</l>
               <l>And those that deny it 'tis out of spight;</l>
               <l>But God send the Mother came honestly by't.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing Lulla, &amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Some Priest, they say, crept nigh her Honour,</l>
               <l>And sprinkled some good Holy Water upon Her,</l>
               <l>Which made her conceive of what has undone Her.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing Lulla, &amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Papists thought themselves greatly blest,</l>
               <l>Before the young Babe was brought to the Test;</l>
               <l>But now they call <hi>Petres</hi> a Fool of a Priest.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing Lulla, &amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Priests in order to fly to the Pope,</l>
               <l>Are got on Board on the Foreign Hope,</l>
               <l>For all that stay here will be sure of a Rope.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing Lulla by Babee, by, by, by.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="song">
            <head>THE Lord Chancellours Villanies Discovered. Or, His <hi>Rise</hi> and <hi>Fall</hi> in the Four last Years.</head>
            <opener>Tune of <hi>Hey brave</hi> Popery, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </opener>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>1.</head>
               <l>GOod People I pray now atrend to my Muse,</l>
               <l>I'le sing of a Villain I cannot abuse,</l>
               <l>The Halter and Axe no such men will refuse;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey brave</hi> Chancellor, <hi>oh fine</hi> Chancellor,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>delicate</hi> Chancellor, <hi>oh,</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <pb n="30" facs="tcp:98643:15"/>
               <head>2.</head>
               <l>'Tis he was the cause of the Nations dismay,</l>
               <l>He hath e're been a Knave from his Birth to this day,</l>
               <l>To see the sot hang'd we will make Holiday.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey brave</hi> Chancellour, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>3.</head>
               <l>And first I will shew what he is in grain;</l>
               <l>I care not a pin for the Boobee's disdain,</l>
               <l>His Deeds now in brief unto you I'le proclaim.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>4.</head>
               <l>He was the Inventer of <hi>Oate's</hi> punishment,</l>
               <l>Front <hi>Newgate</hi> to <hi>Tyburn,</hi> and thither he sent,</l>
               <l>To have him well whipt he gave his consent.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <head>5.</head>
               <l>The good Mr. <hi>Cornish</hi> did innocent dye,</l>
               <l>And all by this Chancellours curst Villany;</l>
               <l>His Blood now from Heaven for Vengeance doth cry.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="6">
               <head>6.</head>
               <l>He was the first Author that open'd his Jaw<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>To take off the <hi>Test</hi> and <hi>Priviledge Laws;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The beheading of <hi>Russel,</hi> 'twas he was the cause.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="7">
               <head>7.</head>
               <l>Then next to the <hi>West</hi> he hurried with speed,</l>
               <l>To murther poor men, a very good deed,</l>
               <l>He made many honest mens hearts for to bleed.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="8">
               <head>8.</head>
               <l>The prisoners to plead to his Lordship did cry,</l>
               <l>But still did make answer, and thus did reply,</l>
               <l>We'll hang you up first, and then after we'll try.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="9">
               <head>9.</head>
               <l>Against their Petitions then he stopt his Ears,</l>
               <l>And still did create all their Doubts and their Fears,</l>
               <l>He left the poor VVidows and Children in Tears.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="10">
               <head>10.</head>
               <l>He was the Inventur that first did promote</l>
               <l>That place call'd the <hi>Ecclesiastical Court,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And thither he made the poor Clergy resort.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="11">
               <head>11.</head>
               <l>Of <hi>Magdalen-College</hi> he thought it most fit</l>
               <l>To turn out the Fellows, a very fine Trick,</l>
               <l>And place Father <hi>Walker,</hi> that curst Jesuite.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="12">
               <head>12.</head>
               <l>Then next to the <hi>Tower</hi> our Bishops he packt,</l>
               <l>And swore he had done a very good Act,</l>
               <l>But now shall be try'd for the matter of Fact.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="13">
               <head>13.</head>
               <l>And when that the Bishops were brought to be try'd,</l>
               <l>To accept a Petition they humbly desir'd;</l>
               <l>He swore he would prove it a Libel to be cry'd,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="14">
               <head>14.</head>
               <l>VVhat can he say now the Parliament sits?</l>
               <l>Alas! they will Vote him quite out of his VVits;</l>
               <l>They'l make him run mad, or fall into Fits.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="15">
               <head>15.</head>
               <l>In <hi>Wapping</hi> he thought for to make his Escape,</l>
               <l>A very good Jest, but I faith it won't take,</l>
               <l>His Head on the Bridge must be stuck on a Stake;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Sing hey,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="16">
               <head>16.</head>
               <l>He many Seditious Lines hath penn'd,</l>
               <l>And sent them to <hi>P</hi>— his Honest Friend;</l>
               <l>My Muse she grows weary, and thus she doth end.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>With pox o'</hi> Chancellour, <hi>villanous</hi> Chancellour,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Damnable</hi> Chancellour, <hi>oh.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>Sir <hi>T. J's</hi> SPEECH TO HIS Wife and Children.</head>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>I.</head>
               <l>DEar Wife, let me have a Fire made,</l>
               <l>I'll tell you such News will make you all glad,</l>
               <l>The like for another is scarce to be had.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is to be Learned and Witty.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <head>II.</head>
               <l>First, (Butler, do you a Glass of Wine bring,)</l>
               <l>I'll tell you all the great Love of my King,</l>
               <l>Which is a dainty, curious fine thing.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>III.</head>
               <l>A Wise Learned Serjeant at Law I was made,</l>
               <l>And a dainty fine Coif was put on my Head,</l>
               <l>VVhich is heavier far than a hundred of Lead.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>IV.</head>
               <l>But soon after this I was made the Recorder,</l>
               <l>To keep the VVorshipful Rabble in order,</l>
               <l>And wore a Red Gown with long Sleeves and Border.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:98643:15"/>
               <head>V.</head>
               <l>What Justice I did, my dear VVife, you can tell;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ight or wrong, I spar'd none, like the Divel in Hell;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t, Guilty or not, I sent all to <hi>Bridewell.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="6">
               <head>VI.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>less it were those that greased my Fist,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o them I gave Licence to cheat whom they list,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or 'twas only those my <hi>Mittimus</hi> miss'd.)</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="7">
               <head>VII.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t then the King dy'd, which caused a pother;</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o I went to condole with the new King, his Brother,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>Vith <hi>Sorrow</hi> in one Hand, and <hi>Grief</hi> in the other.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="8">
               <head>VIII.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or an Ignorant Judge I was call'd by the King</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o the <hi>Chequer-Court,</hi> 'tis a wonderful thing,</l>
               <l>Of which in short time the whole Nation did ring.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="9">
               <head>IX.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>y Great <hi>James</hi> I was rais'd to the <hi>Common-Pleas</hi> Bench,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> Cause he saw I had exquisite Politick Sense,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>Vhich his Wisdom perceiv'd in the Future Tense.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="10">
               <head>X.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t <hi>Sarum</hi> Five hundred Pounds I have gotten,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o save Malefactors from swinging in Cotton,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or which they we hang'd, and now almost rotten.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="11">
               <head>XI.</head>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>t now, my dear Love comes the Cream of the Jest,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or the King would take off the <hi>Oaths</hi> and the <hi>Test;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hich I told all his People would be for the best.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="12">
               <head>XII.</head>
               <l>He had my Opinion, That 'twas in his Power</l>
               <l>To destroy all the Laws in less time than an hour,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or which I may chance to be sent to the <hi>Tower.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="13">
               <head>XIII.</head>
               <l>And now to <hi>Magdalen</hi> College I come,</l>
               <l>VVhere we turn'd out most, but kept in some,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hat so a New College of Priests might have room.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="14">
               <head>XIV.</head>
               <l>And so by that means we left the Door ope,</l>
               <l>To turn out the Bishops and let in the Pope,</l>
               <l>
                  <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#keyers" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>or which we have justly deserved a Rope.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is to be Learned and Witty.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="poem">
            <head>ON THE Prince's going to <hi>England,</hi> WITH AN ARMY, To Restore the Government.</head>
            <epigraph>
               <q>
                  <l>Hunc saltem everso Juvenem succurrere Saeclo</l>
                  <l>Ne prohibete.—</l>
               </q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Virg. Georg. Lib. 1.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </epigraph>
            <l>ONce more a <hi>FATHER</hi> and a <hi>SON</hi> falls out,</l>
            <l>The World involving in their high Dispute;</l>
            <l>Remotest <hi>India</hi>'s <hi>Fate</hi> on <hi>theirs</hi> depends,</l>
            <l>And <hi>Europe,</hi> trembling, the Event attends.</l>
            <l>Their Motions ruling every other State,</l>
            <l>As on the Sun's the lesser Planets wait.</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Power</hi> warms the Father, <hi>Liberty</hi> the Son,</l>
            <l>A Prize, well worth th' uncommon Venture run,</l>
            <l>Him a false Pride to Govern unrestrain'd,</l>
            <l>And by bad Means, bad Ends to be attain'd;</l>
            <l>All Bars of Property drives headlong through.</l>
            <l>Millions oppressing to Inrich a few.</l>
            <l>Him Justice urges, and a Noble Aim</l>
            <l>To equal his Progenitors in Fame,</l>
            <l>And make his Life as Glorious as his Name.</l>
            <l>For Law and Reasons Power he does engage,</l>
            <l>Against the Reign of Appetite and Rage.</l>
            <l>There all the Licence of unbounded Might;</l>
            <l>Here conscious Honour, and deep sense of Right,</l>
            <l>Immortal Enmity to Arms incite.</l>
            <l>Greatness the one, Glory the other Fires,</l>
            <l>This only can deserve what that desires.</l>
            <l>This strives for all that e're to men was dear,</l>
            <l>And he for what they most abhor and fear.</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Caesar</hi> and <hi>Pompey</hi>'s Cause by <hi>Cato</hi> thought</l>
            <l>So ill adjudg'd, to a new Tryal's brought,</l>
            <l>Again at last <hi>Pharsalia</hi> must be fought.</l>
            <l>Ye fatal Sisters! now to <hi>Right</hi> be Friends,</l>
            <l>And make Mankind for <hi>Pompey</hi>'s Fate amends.</l>
            <l>In <hi>Orange</hi>'s Great Line, 'tis no new thing,</l>
            <l>To Free a Nation, and Uncrown a King.</l>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>